Sister...
"There are so many
people on this big old Earth"
"And it's a miracle
that I've met you here"
"The place we're born,
the language we speak"
"The color of our eyes"
"My style, my dreams, my personality"
On the evening of the 7th
a truck and bus collided
in Kiyu Haragi
Naoki Horikawa,
a freshman at a local high school,
was involved in the accident,
and passed away
in a nearby hospital.
The police have not ruled
out the possibility of suicide.
Did you hear?
They said it might be suicide.
What are you saying?
Of course it's suicide.
He was in pretty bad shape.
So what are we gonna do now?
Get something to eat?
I don't know. What do you think?
I don't know if I've got time...
Time? Time for what?
- No...
- You've got time.
- Actually...
- What? What's the problem?
Sister...
Save me.
I'm sorry.
Naoki...
"Game over"
Are you okay?
Yeah. I'm fine.
Sorry, Shun.
No.
You just kept saying you were sorry.
Um... Horikawa...
You can call me Anna. What is it?
Well... What do you think?
It's a really exciting game.
I'm surprised
you've got a talent like this.
Talent?
It's really nothing that special...
You just got caught here, but
you can hide in the next room.
I see.
As you play the game, you can
choose the wrong route, right?
Yeah.
Do you have to start over from
where you made the mistake?
You don't need to
start over, actually.
You don't?
There's a special program
that activates if you don't give up
even when things get really bad.
A special program?
Yeah. You ran into this
room and couldn't go on, right?
Even if you make this choice...
It's made so that if don't
give up, you can survive.
It's like... the strength
to open the door you closed,
And face the danger.
The strength to face the danger?
Yeah. Actually there's similar
programs besides this one.
This closet.
There's a slightly
different program...
There's a secret item inside this desk.
What happened to your hand?
I'm fine. It's nothing.
Sorry to keep you out here so late.
It's fine.
The game was really fun.
Thanks for coming today.
I was happy when you talked to me.
Since you just moved here
there's probably a lot
you don't understand.
Ask me anything.
Yeah.
Let's go home together.
I want to do some maintenance,
so go home without me.
Got it.
Bye.
Talent, she said.
What are you doing out here?
Nothing.
Oh?
You're shaking.
Are you sick?
I have to get home.
You don't look like you're doing so well.
You should lie down.
Give that back!
You're funny.
An escape game? What, did you make this?
This looks fun.
Stop it!
Hey.
What is that?
I'm sorry.
"Blue Green Ghost"
I want to go home.
My mom's gonna worry.
You're such a mama's boy, Takeshi.
That's why Takuro bullies you.
That's not it.
I've got good reasons.
I know that!
Oh, Takuro!
Okay, let's do some work.
More drugs?
Don't say that.
Wait, does it really
have to be here, Takuro?
What are you scared of?
This place is you know.
It's fine!
We can leave them here and
nobody will find them.
I spread a rumor that
there were ghosts here.
Right, Mika?
The Jailhouse.
But...
Takeshi...
Calm down.
Don't worry about a thing.
We're best buddies, right?
Yeah...
I'm counting on you, best bud.
Come on, hurry.
The sun's going to set.
Yeah. Takeshi, you push it.
Hey!
Mommy!
- Shut up!
- Takeshi's scared!
He doesn't want to go!
Stop talking about that.
This place is scary!
Stop it.
Huh?
Hey.
Hiroshi?
This is my territory, man.
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't
think anybody lived here.
Forget the excuses.
Just tell me what you're doing here.
Have you ever heard of holometabolism?
Huh?
It's when an insect transforms
via a cocoon.
Don't you think it's a
strange, wonderful mystery?
A caterpillar turns into a butterfly.
And I'm going to see it!
And just a while ago,
I caught a bombardier beetle.
When a bombardier beetle is in danger,
they emit a noxious
spray out of their butt!
Can you believe that?
Isn't it wonderfully mysterious?
And the way the bombardier beetle
starts to panic
and resist when you catch it...
It's so cute! So cute! So cute!
Listen.
I'm not asking about the bugs.
I'm asking about you.
Oh, sorry.
I'm not interested in human
biology at all,
nor in myself.
Shut up-
Your faces...
You're too scared.
I'm going to go finish
something. You guys wait here.
Don't let anybody in.
Mika, let's go.
Wait a second!
Come on, hurry.
Takuro!
What are we going to do?
Yes.
The door... that sound...
this is interesting.
I'll go take a look.
You guys are all crazy, coming
into a creepy place like this!
Takeshi, wait!
"Reject. Answer"
Hello?
"No signal"
Hey, hello?
What? No signal? Darn it!
I'm sure it's Takuro...
Takuro! Hurry up!
Takeshi, what was that?
- Takeshi!
- Oh no! Oh no!
What's wrong? Calm down!
Why won't it open?
Calm down!
Takeshi!
Takeshi, wait!
Shun?
Anna...
Why, Anna?
There was something I wanted to check out.
More importantly, what
happened? Takeshi was acting weird.
We saw something.
Something weird, a guy
we've never seen before.
But... I think I've seen
him before, somehow!
You've seen him? What do you mean?
I don't know.
Anna, let's get out of
here! I've got a bad feeling!
But Shun, the front door won't open,
and all the windows are closed.
That's impossible...
Let's go.
We should get everybody back together.
Shun! Please.
Follow me.
What is this place?
Takuro! Takuro! Where did you go?
I can't take anymore! No more!
What is this place? Darn it!
The door... the door...
This is it.
Okay,
let's stash the stuff down here.
It's kind of creepy.
Not you too.
Well, it is creepy.
I'd never come here if I didn't need to.
So like, I know it's creepy, but...
What, exactly, is creepy?
What are you trying to say is here?
A ghost.
A ghost?
That's hilarious. I haven't
talked about ghosts in years.
Come on, don't be
stupid. Let's finish this up.
I'm going down, you wait here.
Mika? What's wrong?
There's something
here! It was looking at me!
Calm down.
There may be someone here.
Forgot it! Let's just go!
Let's not do this, Hiroshi.
Don't scare me, idiot!
Takeshi!
Hey, Takeshi!
There's something here! I saw it!
Takuro's always like this.
It was the same with Naoki...
Takeshi!
If you say another
word, Takuro will kill you.
Takeshi, there's no point in staying here.
Let's go outside.
This building's kind of weird.
Weird?
Takeshi!
I'm staying here!
Our parents are going to start to freak out
when we don't come home.
And then they'll find us!
I'll stay here until that happens.
I'm not doing that. I want to
get out of here as fast as I can.
You can do what you want!
Alright.
Anyway, we're heading outside.
When we get out,
we'll call your parents,
so stay here until then.
Alright?
Takeshi? May I borrow that?
Do what you want.
Thank you.
Bye. Wimp.
What?
Anna!
What are you doing here?
- Well...
- Tell me!
Anna.
Did anything strange happen?
The front door just
wouldn't open all of a sudden.
Where are the others?
There's one shivering in there.
Where's Takuro?
I don't know. I lost him midway.
Takuro might know something, maybe.
Where do you suppose he is?
I can't take anymore... I want to go home.
Why do I have to stay here?
Freaking Takuro...
Hello? Can you hear me?
The Jailhouse! The Jailhouse!
Behind the abandoned school!
Hello?
Darn it!
Hey, Takeshi.
Takuro!
What's wrong? You okay?
Takuro, let's get out of
here! There's a monster...
What was that?
Let's go.
Save me!
Takeshi!
Takeshi! Takeshi!
Takeshi! What's wrong? Takeshi!
Takeshi...
I don't know who did it,
but we need to get out of here!
Hey, where's the key to the front door?
Takuro's got it, right?
Mika, where is Takuro right now?
I don't know...
We got separated!
Mika!
We need to hurry.
Takeshi's been brutally
killed, do you understand?
What are you trying to protect?
What is Takuro doing here?
Shut up!
I don't need to tell you.
What are you hiding?
What are you talking about?
What did Takeshi mean when
he mentioned Naoki back there?
You said if he said anymore,
Takuro would kill him.
I don't know.
What is Takuro doing here?
I don't know!
It's got nothing to do with me!
- Tell me why Naoki died?
- I said I don't know!
Mika!
Shun, we need to go, too!
Shun? Shun?
Anna...
Shun, we need to hurry and get out of here!
Am I dreaming?
Huh?
Do you remember this feeling?
It's the same.
It's the exact same as the game I made!
Who's there?
Takuro!
Mika, you were
watching up there, right?
Listen, Takuro!
Takeshi... He's dead.
He was killed!
What?
There's a monster here!
We need to hurry or we'll be killed!
A ghost?
You've been using too many
drugs, haven't you Mika?
It's true!
Sure, sure. Just keep
watch. I'll be done soon.
I'll give you plenty of attention later,
so just wait a second.
No, Takuro...
I can't hold back anymore.
It's okay, right?
Sure.
Sure, I guess.
I like that.
Bye, Takuro.
Huh? You're not going to finish?
What is this place?
Anna, would you pull a book off
the bookshelf
at the same time I do?
This book.
Alright.
Ready...
This?
A key?
I knew it.
It's the same as the game?
Why?
Hey, Shun.
Anna!
Let's run!
Why?
Takuro?
Hiroshi?
Mika?
Mika! Mika! Are you there?
Mika! Mika!
Mika!
It opened.
Next is the piano room.
Shun.
Open the door.
Mika...
Shun, no!
That's not Mika!
Anna... Shun... save me!
Anna? Why?
Shun...
Mika would never call for you.
Please. Believe me.
She wouldn't call for me?
Shun?
Shun!
Shun! Shun! Shun!
Save me, Shun. I'm Mika.
Save me!
The Ao Oni!
Anna, this way!
Here!
There's a handkerchief inside
here. You put the liquid soap on it...
Shun!
Hurry!
Anna, hurry!
Mika...
Shun, where do we go next?
The piano room. Wipe the keys
with this and you'll see a code.
You can use it to open the safe
in the next room
to get a key.
Roll back the carpet in the storeroom
and you'll see a secret staircase...
How did you know
it wasn't Mika back there?
You...
You look like Naoki.
Did anybody ever tell
you about my little brother?
Naoki Horikawa,
who died six months ago.
He's two years younger than me,
and we went to the same school.
Since we were so close in
age, we fought all the time.
But Naoki...
He was being bullied.
I could tell it, somehow, so I
asked Naoki a bunch of times.
You can tell your big
sister anything, I'd say.
But he always said he was okay.
And he'd smile.
Whenever he smiled and
said he was okay, it was a lie.
You're a lot like him.
Naoki is telling me that.
Naoki is telling you?
Is that how you knew about the Ao Oni?
Do you believe me?
Anna! I'm so glad you're safe.
Hiroshi...
Mika?
Hiroshi,
we may be able to get out of here.
Alright. Let's go.
No, Takuro.
I can't hold back anymore...
Hey... it's okay, right?
Mika?
I can't hold back anymore either!
Anna, what is this?
This is a game.
- A game?
- It's a game world.
A game world? How unrealistic...
Next we go to the storeroom
and roll back the carpet.
And then we'll see the
entrance to the basement.
Anna?
Let's end this game. Come on.
It's open.
Let's go.
What are you doing here?
Not that it matters.
Why? Why are you doing this?
If you don't leave with us, you'll die.
Die? Huh?
Don't be stupid.
Did you kill him?
I don't have the slightest
clue who you're talking about.
Anna...
Your brother died on his own, okay?
I was just a little mean to him.
We're going to end this. Right, Shun?
Shun?
Yes. This is a game Shun made.
A game?
Oh, do you like this stuff?
Do you?
You took Shun and...
Anna...
Stop talking about Shun all the darn time.
Out with it.
What do you want to say?
I knew it.
Are you talking about that?
Shun...
You're getting creepy.
Anna Horikawa.
What was that?
Takeshi!
Shun?
Anna...
Shun, Mika wouldn't call for you.
She wouldn't call for me?
How did you know it wasn't Mika?
Am I dreaming?
I don't understand.
Do you believe what I'm saying?
Seriously?
You know all that...
You can't leave alive.
Shun... you may not be able to believe it.
But Takuro killed my
brother Naoki, and you too!
Shun was using my name in a game he made!
It really made me mad!
Shun is right here.
Oh? And?
A ghost?
No way. I'm done talking with you.
He's been with me this
whole time, helping me.
I thought he was alive like us.
Right, Shun?
But I'm sorry.
I knew the whole time.
When I came here, you were already...
Shun?
Honestly...
I wanted to take care of that
and go home with everybody.
The only thing I can do...
is give you a peaceful death.
It would be better if you died.
You're the ones...
who are going to die.
No, you're the one who's going to die.
Save me! Save me!
Hiroshi! Hiroshi!
Anna? Hurry!
- Hiroshi!
- Let's go! Now!
Hiroshi!
Anna... leave me and go.
No! Hiroshi, hurry!
Anna!
Please!
Survive.
Run!
Shun!
I don't know what to do!
I don't know!
I can't remember what to do!
Anna.
Anna! Anna! Anna! Anna!
There's a special program
that activates if you don't give up
even when things get really bad.
Naoki would always
say it's okay, and smile...
Whenever he smiled and
said he was okay, it was a lie.
- Anna! Anna! Anna!
- It hurt...
Anna! Anna! Anna!
I'm okay.
Why? Why do you say you're okay?
Anna. Let's go.
Yeah.
Shun...
Anna? What's wrong?
Are you okay?
I'm sorry. Was it that scary?
No.
I just remembered a lot of stuff.
The strength to face the danger, was it?
- Huh?
- That special program you made.
Yeah.
Shun...
I couldn't save my
little brother.
Tell me anything.
Anything.
Yeah.
Thanks.
"Clear"
OCR done by
CH
IZ
R
"Next stage"
"This movie is a work of fiction"
"and all characters and places
in it are fictional."