- This is a terrible scene.
- Four people…
A survivor!
She was restrained. She says
she is the housekeeper of this home.
Do you understand the situation?
I don't know…
Both the parents and the children…
They were all wonderful people.
Truly… Such a lovely…
An ideal family…
3 MONTHS AGO
HAIBARA FAMILY
Papa! Come here for a sec.
What? I'm about to leave.
I'm stopping by the
dealer before work today.
I already told you, didn't I?
Today's the day the housekeeper is coming.
- Kuromi Kioka-san.
- Nice to meet you, sir.
I am the housekeeper, Kuromi.
Pleased to be working with you.
Pretty young.
Even so, I've been a
housekeeper for seven years.
My husband works as an
executive at the company.
I haven't given you my card yet, have I?
Allow me to introduce
myself again, Haibara Midori.
I'll take it.
Oh, who’s this?
I am the housekeeper, Kuromi.
You must be the eldest son, Chiaki-sama.
Oh, Kuromi-chan? Nice to meet you.
The eldest daughter, Akari-sama, is in
her second year of middle school, correct?
- Yes…
- She’s been withdrawn,
and not attending school lately.
- I'm worried too.
- I see.
Well, do your best!
I'm off!
I need to go too.
Take care.
- Be careful.
- Okay.
Well then, madam,
I’d like to take a look around the house.
Would you mind giving me a tour?
Oh… Yes, of course.
I was planning to tidy up
before you arrive, Kuromi-san.
But things have been so busy…
Madam…
Please don't do this again.
I'm sorry.
The job of a housekeeper
is to handle household chores
so that the madam
can focus on work.
So.. Please do not feel
ashamed in front of me.
You have great talent in management.
That’s right.
I worked hard and earned enough
to afford such a big house.
Yes, truly admirable.
KASEIFU KUROMI WA KUSATTA KAZOKU WO YURUSANAI
(THE HOUSEKEEPER KUROMI WON'T FORGIVE ROTTEN FAMILIES)
ENGLISH SUBTITLES BY CHRIZ KAYRIKO
Visit chrizkayriko.github.io
My skills as a housekeeper
will be put to the test.
Akari-sama?
I would love to meet you soon.
This is...
Yes, then the decision is
made to open the 10th store.
Send the documents once
they are compiled. Thanks.
Yes, good work.
That's right, just as Kuromi-san said,
my abilities should be directed toward
something more productive than housework.
There’s no need to feel guilty
about not being good at housework.
Yes?
Midori!
Huh? You seem to be in a good mood today.
Huh? Do I?
There was another interview request. A
feature on "Shining Women Entrepreneurs."
It would be good publicity,
so maybe I'll accept it.
You're becoming even more famous.
Oh, right. Since Midori seemed busy,
I went ahead and approved
the new beauty device purchase.
Ah, thanks as always, Makiko. That helps.
You're welcome.
Excuse me.
I brought something that was forgotten.
Kuromi-san, sorry for the trouble.
Thank you.
- See you.
- Yes, please take care of it.
Thank you.
She is my business partner, Sudou Makiko.
Originally a friend, we
started this company together
and worked hard to grow it this big.
A wonderful friendship.
Wow, unbelievable!
Amazing, right? It looks so beautiful now.
Wow! This place is actually this spacious?
Oh?
This is…
Kuromi-san, where did you find this photo?
I found it while tidying up.
It was such a lovely photo,
so I decided to display it.
Thank you.
Wow, is all of this handmade by Kuromi-san?
Yes, I hope it suits your taste.
This might be the first time having
such amazing food in this house.
Akari.
She's Kuromi-san.
Akari-sama, if there is anything that
cannot be eaten, please let me know.
Come on, at least say hello properly.
Truly, a wonderful home…
Ah, the new product.
I thought I should tidy it up properly.
But things have been so busy...
Wonderful!
It's okay, Madam.
Kuromi will...
raise you to be a person
worthy of being my master.
And then...
A husband who is only an executive in name.
An eldest daughter who
seems to be carrying darkness.
An eldest son who is unnaturally friendly.
All of you...
will become the ideal
family worthy of my service.
Please watch over me.
Wow, I’m so happy.
Are you enjoying yourselves?
Everyone, are you having a good time?
Midori-san, you look
even more beautiful today.
- Oh my, how flattering!
- The food was amazing.
- And the house has such great taste.
- I was truly surprised.
I wish I had been invited sooner.
There’s also a special dessert prepared,
so if anyone still has room,
please do enjoy it.
This dessert...
was made exactly
according to Madam’s recipe.
- It looks delicious!
- I absolutely have to try it!
Kuromi-san...
The tableware, the food,
it’s all thanks to you.
It’s an honor to be of service.
Since it seems popular,
I will bring out more dessert.
Please do.
- It’s a nice party.
- Konno-sama.
Thanks to this,
I was able to build connections.
I’m honored that you enjoyed it.
It’s a nice house.
Honestly, I’m surprised.
- Huh?
- Well...
You never invited anyone over,
so everyone was talking about it. Right?
Exactly. Beautiful CEO Haibara Midori...
might have some deep reason
why she can’t invite people to her house...
No way! Come on...
That was close...
As expected, people were suspicious.
If they found out
that it was actually a garbage house...
Kuromi-san really is amazing.
That housekeeper...
I knew I had seen her somewhere before.
It was at the
Yanagisawa family’s party.
The Yanagisawa family?
The former minister’s?
Yes! She’s very popular, and apparently,
it’s hard to get a contract with her.
Haibara-san, you’re really lucky.
I was surprised by the wonderful party.
Before you came,
it was completely different.
Truly impressive.
No… I did nothing.
I'm just assisting according
to Madam’s instructions.
I see… You’re tight-lipped too.
I heard from Midori, you're
still in the trial period, right?
Yes. I'll work first for three months,
then Madam will make a decision.
Isn’t it actually you who
is evaluating instead?
I knew it.
Hey, I’ll pay double the
salary, come work for me.
I think I suit you better.
No way! She's planning to poach!?
I'm honored.
But unless Madam dismisses me,
I have decided to serve.
Until Madam passes away.
Huh?
Wait, Makiko, don’t take Kuromi-san.
Don't try to poach.
You’re single, you don’t
even need a housekeeper.
Are you mocking me for
being unable to marry?
Huh? No, could you not misunderstand?
I chose to be single
for work, unlike Midori.
- Huh?
- Do you even realize?
Encouraging to start a business, teaching
the clueless Midori everything, it was me.
If not for me, Midori would’ve
been just another esthetician.
And yet, you're obsessed with standing out,
you're accepting any interview possible…
Is that really how you saw me?
You're just a fabricated creation.
Hey, wouldn’t it be interesting
if the world found out Midori's secret?
Isn't the parasite infesting
Madam’s company actually you?
Huh?
These high-end beauty
devices, 20 units were purchased...
But is that true? Falsifying
the number of units,
didn't somone embezzle the payment?
How does an outsider like
you have the right to say that?
You have no right to suspect anything and
it has already been confirmed with Midori.
Madam has known all along that
Sudo-sama had been embezzling.
Everything is already known.
Huh?
Until now, Madam simply
chose not to sue out of generosity.
Isn’t that right, Madam?
Yes…
You're not feeling well, are you?
Shall I arrange a taxi for Sudo-sama?
Yes.
Let’s go.
Kuromi-san!
What’s the matter, Madam?
It's really good that you came.
I've been fighting alone all this time.
The company and the house... I thought
I had to handle everything by myself.
Kuromi-san, please,
stay in this house forever.
Support me!
Without you, I...
I can't...
Of course, Madam.
Forever and ever...
As long as you are alive…
I will never leave.
Thank you.
Madam, is something the matter?
Makiko suddenly handed me this...
A letter of resignation...
There's been no contact since then.
Someone that irresponsible
is not needed in your company.
Besides, someone who embezzles money...
But without Makiko, I...
You have already been recognized by
the world as a respectable business leader.
You will be fine on your own.
Do you think so?
Absolutely.
Please have more confidence in yourself.
3 DAYS AGO
What is this? Calling
me out to a place like this.
That scarf… It looks very much like
something Madam owns. How lovely.
Do you intend to
expose Madam's secret?
You're sharp.
If people found out that the president
of a beauty company has such a secret...
It would be a disaster.
The company's credibility would be gone,
and if that husband found
out, the family would fall apart?
I ask that you never see Madam again.
That’s not happening.
Are you requesting hush money?
Don't be mistaken!
I just want to see it. The face
of Midori in pain, in sorrow!
To see that face, I would spend
my entire life getting in her way!
Again and again!
That can’t be helped, then.
Huh?
Jealousy arises from the
awareness of inferiority.
- What?
- And then...
As a sin of humankind…
The one that produces
the ugliest endings is...
Jealousy.
A pest that tries to destroy the
Haibara family out of ugly jealousy
deserves to be eradicated.
Hello.
There are many pests in this house...
ENGLISH SUBTITLES BY CHRIZ KAYRIKO
Visit chrizkayriko.github.io
NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW
THIS DRAMA IS FICTION
THE CHARACTERS AND ORGANIZATIONS FEATURED ARE FICTITIOUS.