I am Kuromi, the housekeeper.
A housekeeper is responsible
for household chores.
Please do not feel ashamed in front of me.
Such a truly wonderful home.
Pests deserve to be exterminated.
Kuromi-san, please support me.
Everyone must become the ideal family.
Hey.
Is this shirt a bit too flashy?
It looks very good.
I see.
- Good morning.
Ah, first period is P.E.
Where's my gym uniform?
I ironed it for you.
Thanks.
Late again? You stayed out
playing at night, didn't you?
I was studying since it's almost test time.
Aren't you about to go
out and have fun yourself?
I am an executive at Midori's company.
I’m busy with important work.
Important work? In that outfit?
No, this is, you see...
Sir.
You forgot something.
Huh? Oh, right.
I was going to change before work.
I see.
I'm off!
Guess I’ll head out to work too.
Please take care.
Have a good day.
Cleaning will be finished soon.
I will prepare lunch.
Huh? That’s all for cleaning?
Once a big cleanup is done,
daily maintenance is enough.
Even with a little cleaning each day,
a house does not get dirty.
Please rest assured.
As long as I am here,
any dirt will be cleaned.
Is there anything in particular
you would like for lunch?
- No need.
- However...
You did not eat breakfast either.
I can take care of myself,
so do not mind me.
KASEIFU KUROMI WA KUSATTA KAZOKU WO YURUSANAI
(THE HOUSEKEEPER KUROMI WON'T FORGIVE ROTTEN FAMILIES)
ENGLISH SUBTITLES BY CHRIZ KAYRIKO
Visit chrizkayriko.github.io
Huh? Oh, the reason for skipping school?
That child won't say clearly.
Well, not a talkative one to begin with.
Lately, she barely speaks at all.
I see.
It was my fault too.
I was busy with work,
even from a young age...
I didn't really give attention to her.
Instead, I thought I was
giving her enough allowance.
What has been said to
the school and neighbors?
Akari is weak,
so we said she is taking
time off from school.
If she's being bullied,
I’m thinking of transferring
her to a boarding school.
Could you try to find out why
Akari is not attending school?
Understood.
I think it’s impossible.
Even if you try to get
something out of Akari.
Why is that?
Akari doesn't open up
to anyone in the family.
I don’t think she’ll open up to you either.
And that kid…
Kuromi-san, will you keep this a secret?
No matter what, I will absolutely
protect the family secrets.
I just found this online by chance,
Isn’t this Akari?
I’ve heard of a kid making
money by taking pictures like this,
but I never thought it would be Akari.
Akari isn’t lacking money.
Maybe it's to get back at Mom.
She probably wants to trouble Mom, who is only
focused on work and doesn’t care about her.
Well, I can understand that feeling.
Have you told your mom about this?
Of course not.
Mom cares about how things look to others.
If this got out, our
family would be finished.
Hey, isn't the delivery here yet?
I've been waiting over an hour.
I wonder what happened?
Maybe they got into an accident.
I was just making hamburgers right now.
Would you like some?
No thanks.
Mmm… it’s delicious.
Please eat gently.
Cocoa. How did you know I liked it?
That mug is from a cocoa
maker in the Netherlands, right?
I think it’s a special item you can
only get when you subscribe regularly.
I remember it well.
You know a lot.
When I was little, Mom made it for me,
and I’ve loved it ever since.
What’s this?
It’s really delicious.
The trick is to roast a
little cocoa powder first.
I found this while cleaning the closet.
It’s Akari-sama’s report card and test
results from when she went to school.
She was really excellent.
With this, there should be no problem
even if you resume going to school.
It's been over six
months. I can't catch up.
Actually, I used to work as a tutor.
Huh?
Well, since this is a right angle...
Please take a good look at the shape.
Ah, I see. It's the Pythagorean theorem.
- Correct.
- Well done.
If it’s Akari-sama, even if
she returns to school now,
her grades will still be top class.
But still, I can't go to school.
Akari-sama...
Are you being threatened by someone?
Huh?
Don’t worry. I’ll never tell your mother.
Sakuma-sensei from middle school.
He's a part-time teacher.
He was fun, kind, and
popular with the girls.
- Good morning.
He was always concerned about
me, someone with few friends,
and often spoke to me.
I also looked forward to talking to him.
If the next test is 100
points, I'll think about it.
Eh!?
If there's something you don't understand,
come ask me anytime.
Yeah, thank you.
- You must have studied a lot.
- Yeah, I worked hard.
But one day, after school,
He told me he'd help me
study, so I went to the art room.
As soon as we were
alone, his attitude changed...
Huh, what are you doing, teacher?
Haibara, you hardly ever smile in class.
Why is that?
I know.
Haibara, you have a wonderful
smile that no one else can beat.
I'm a loner, and I have few friends.
I see. No one around you has
noticed your true charm until now.
Poor Haibara.
But it's okay now.
I'll capture your lovely smile
forever in a photo for you.
I'll make sure your smile is preserved.
So I were photographed...
But then, I thought it was wrong,
and tried to get the photos deleted.
“If you don’t want
your parents to find out,
come back to the art
room tomorrow after school.
If you don’t want to go to school,
come to the hotel now.
I’ll take cute pictures of you.”
There was a girl in my class
who refused to go to school before,
and her embarrassing photos
were sold on the internet.
I heard the rumor.
Could it be about me?
Let's report this man
to the police right now.
I don't want the police. If
Mom and school find out,
I won’t be able to
return to school anymore.
You really wanted to go to
school, didn't you, Akari-sama?
It’s okay now.
This Kuromi will cleanse
Akari-sama’s troubled heart
and make it beautiful.
AKARI: TEACHER, I WOULD LIKE TO MEET YOU.
COULD YOU COME TO THE STATION THIS AFTERNOON?
TEACHER: I'VE ALREADY ARRIVED.
SORRY, AN URGENT
MATTER CAME UP. I CAN'T GO.
Huh? Don't mess with me.
Are you serious?
- Hey, hey, big brother.
- Huh?
Do you know of any cheap
internet cafes around here?
I’m having trouble because
I don’t have any money.
I see.
That’s a problem.
When you run out of money, you
always do things like this, don't you?
You seem used to it.
LET'S STUDY TOGETHER!
IF YOU DON'T WANT TO BE
EXPOSED, COME TO THE HOTEL.
MOMOKA: I JUST ARRIVED AT THE HOTEL.
I WILL GO, SO PLEASE DON'T TELL ANYONE.
Someone like you, so sinful, should fall.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Huh? she’s not here.
Are you serious!?
It’s not gone.
I thought I was lucky.
Damn it!
Is this Sakuma-san?
We received a report just now.
Regarding obscene images of a minor.
We’d like to ask you a few questions.
If possible, would you
come with us to the station?
Understood.
Hey, wait!
Hey!
Hey! Stop!
Hey, wait!
Stop! There’s no use in running.
Stop!
Wait, Sakuma!
Hey, there’s no use in running!
Stop!
Sakuma, hey, wait!
- Oh no, someone’s fallen.
- Huh? Oh no.
- Oh no. Wow, oh no.
- I’ve never seen this before.
- Will this go viral?
- Huh? It seems like it might.
- Oh no.
- Are you okay?
Are you alive?
- Mom, listen…
- Hmm?
I’m thinking of going to
school starting tomorrow.
Huh, really?
Yeah. Is that okay?
Of course.
Of course!
Ah, but why suddenly?
Kuromi-san taught me how to study, and
I think I can keep up with the lessons now.
I see. Mom is so happy.
I’ll go get ready for school.
I’m glad to hear that, Madam.
It’s all thanks to you.
I’m really glad you came.
It’s nothing.
If it’s your request,
I’ll do anything for you.
Well, if you don’t mind,
there’s one thing I would like to ask you.
Mom, what’s wrong?
Would you like to have a drink?
Did you make this
because Kuromi-san told you to?
Did you figure it out?
You were still using this cup.
I used to make cocoa
for you a lot back then.
Yeah.
Want to come in for a bit?
Is that okay?
Yeah.
Kuromi-san taught me
the Pythagorean theorem.
- Pythagorean?
- Yeah, and then…
This is what an ideal family looks like.
Isn’t that right?
Well, I’m off.
Yes, take care.
Is something wrong?
Do you know why I
decided to go back to school?
MALE PART-TIME TEACHER FALLS TO HIS DEATH
(TN: I shortened the
headline because it's so long.)
Well. It's an unfortunate accident.
Did Kuromi-san do something?
I am a housekeeper.
All I can do is
clean up the dirt that
has settled in this house.
Well, I’m off then.
Take care,
and have a good day.
This is…
The housekeeper of this house is busy.
NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW
ENGLISH SUBTITLES BY CHRIZ KAYRIKO
Visit chrizkayriko.github.io
THIS DRAMA IS FICTION