Who is the last person you want to see?
This is the other side of goodbye.
The other side of goodbye...
I
I'm dead, aren't I?
The last person you want to see...
Who is that?
GOODBYE MY DEAR
I never thought I'd die like this.
Maybe I'll make a hand-rolled sushi.
Tofa! Tofa!
Somebody, somebody stop him!
Catch him!
A dog ran out into the road.
You saved him.
It's not my dog though.
I think
I'm stupid.
Rather, I think you were a hero.
Hero?
Is there anyone you'd like to see?
That's it. What do you mean, "last"?
After you passed away... you
visited this other side of goodbye.
You'll be given time to meet once more with
the people of this world,
only for 24 hours.
You will look no different
from before you die
and you can see anyone again.
Also, they will know that you exist.
Therefore, you can touch
and talk to each other.
- You can hug them too.
- I want to see them.
I want to see them.
I want to see them!
But there is a condition,
you can meet
the only people who do
not know that you are dead.
I'm back! Welcome back!
- I'm home!
- Welcome back!
Oh, Yuta, wash your hands first.
Wash your hands and change your clothes.
- I've got snacks for you.
- Wow!
For those people that knows you are dead,
you cannot meet them.
Wait, I don't understand.
This is the other side of goodbye.
Okay, I got that!
You are a rational person, aren't you?
You are indeed a middle
school science teacher,
Ayako Sakuraba.
Do you know me?
I'm the guide.
The guide?
I am with you, until the end.
In short, you are a reaper.
- The guide.
- Can't you do something about that rule?
Just because the wake and the
funeral are already over,
it doesn't mean I won't be
able to see them anymore!
Is there any other person you want to see?
No way...
That doesn't make any sense!
What am I going to do
about it? Grim Reaper!
- The guide.
- So do something!
Why are these rules
established? I will explain.
No, that's okay.
I don't need you to explain.
What if I meet someone
who knows I'm dead?
If you meet someone who knows you're dead,
at that moment your image will disappear.
You will be returned here.
I see.
Do you understand?
When I bought a denim
jacket at a special sale,
I asked them why it was so cheap.
The clerk said, "Actually, there's a
weave flaw in a place you can't see.",
he explained.
Similar to how I felt at the time,
something just clicked in my gut.
Something clicked in your gut.
That's it.
A denim jacket?
I found a nice one.
I see.
But...
Yes?
I've decided, I really want to see them!
Can't you do something
just for tonight?
No, so just for tonight.
I'm working day shift from next week.
Yuta.
Yuta?
Yuta, put on your socks.
What's up?
What shall we do for dinner?
Where shall we go for dinner?
- Anything.
- Eh?
Anything.
Here... here.
- Yuta, you know...
- Yes?
Can you stay by yourself tonight?
(I'll be fine.
I'll be fine.
- It's mama.
- Eh?
I smell mama.
I see. What does it smell like?
Sunshine?
Warm smell.
Smells good.
It's the smell of the sun.
The smell of the sun.
A little big though,
but it looks good on you.
- It's cool.
- Really?
Yeah.
Toya!
If you meet someone
who knows you are dead,
at that moment
your image will disappear.
You will be returned here.
- Toya!
Not really.
His friend Yohei-kun too.
Kosuke wants to do that too.
They want it
but he's being unreasonable.
It's just them and Yuta.
He's smiling all by himself.
But what's wrong with that?
I don't think he's assertive enough.
English Conversation, Swimming Class.
He also tried a trial piano course.
He tried all of them.
"How do you like it?
Do you want to try again?" I asked him.
He said "No problem."
It wasn't something he
could be interested in.
If it's something he really
want to do, he'd want it.
"What do you want to do?" I asked him.
- "I'm fine" he said.
- Maybe it's a habit of him.
"I'm fine."
I really want to hear
the true "I'm fine".
I want to hear it too.
Toya! Toya, Toya...
Toya!!!
Toya, Toya.
Oh, I've been beaten! And
and then,
Toya! I got you!
- Yuta, are you okay?
- I'm fine.
You're not okay.
I'm going to help you.
I'm okay.
- Toya!
- Oh, I got hit but I won't let go!
Other than that,
is there anyone else you want to meet?
ISHIBASHI
You called me, are you Sakuraba-san?
Yes, I am.
Excuse me, I'm dressed like this.
- It's nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
Um... where is Ishibashi-sensei?
Please come in.
I was thinking,
when you call me,
I will let him know.
I thought that he were here.
- I'm sorry, I asked...
- No.
He passed away about 2 years ago.
After he retired from teaching,
he went across the station.
He took a leisurely
stroll along the riverside.
On that day too,
he was taking a walk as usual.
Shouting loudly to the
children who are making noise.
He noticed and ran over to them...
No way...
He jumped into the river to help.
The child was saved
but my father was left untouched.
I don't know if he's too
old for this or he's just reckless.
- I'm back.
- Welcome back.
I'm hungry.
Then, take off your
hat. Put the cage down.
There's a snack in the kitchen.
- Wash your hands first.
- Okay.
Ah... this is my daughter, Sae.
- Hello.
Are you a friend of my grandfather?
- I'm he's student.
- A student?
For your grandfather,
long time ago,
he took care of me so much.
He is my benefactor.
- Benefactor?
- Someone very dear to me.
Heh, well, have a good time!
- Okay.
- You wash your hands first, okay?
Yes.
I don't think she
understands it well yet,
the death of my father.
The fact that he is not here anymore,
she knows that.
But that doesn't mean that he's dead,
or we're not connected
anymore, or something.
Death itself,
I don't think she understands it
because she is still a child.
She thinks she'll see him again someday.
Well, just now,
you said you owe my father a favor.
Uh... yes.
When I was in junior high school,
I was almost bullied in class.
I was shunned and
laughed at for no reason.
It is a kind of game.
Most adults,
they don't want to
complicate matters even more,
but Ishibashi-sensei
was indeed good.
Putting his self in every child's shoes.
Not making things worse,
with his reasoned judgment,
he guided us.
Sakuraba-san,
- are you a science teacher by any chance?
- Yes, I am.
Oh, my father told me something.
She told me that one of his students became
a science teacher at a junior high school.
It's me.
I was so happy to hear it.
You remembered me, didn't you?
She said she had a strong sense of justice.
She was a straight girl.
That is because
Ishibashi-sensei was like that.
It was my ideal.
For the sake of the children,
jumping into the river,
if it was Ishibashi-sensei,
I'm sure that's what he would have done.
Indeed,
I think it was a very fatherly choice.
He was brave until the end.
It's just,
As a daughter,
I wanted him to live.
Mr. reaper.
Guide.
I can go away now.
- There is still time.
- I'll give it to you.
No, you can have it.
You've been allowed 24 hours.
Enough!
I wanted to hug them.
Once more, with my hands,
I wanted to hold that child in my arms.
Before you give up
and want to try again,
please try to remember.
SAKURABA-SENSEI
THANK YOU SO MUCH
GRADE 10 4TH CLASS
Yuta.
Mama.
Mama, are you back?
Welcome home!
She don't seem to
understand it well yet.
I don't think she understands death itself.
She is still a child.
Yuta, Yuta!
Thank you.
You're protecting a
distant star, aren't you?
- Distant star?
- Yohei said.
Mama, away from the earth,
distant stars,
he says you're protecting it.
He says it's cool.
It's like Earth Defense Forces.
- Yuta.
- Oh, wait a minute!
Toya! Toya!
Karate? Do you want to learn it?
I'm already learning it.
What's going on?
Se-ec-ret!
Huh? Tell me. Tell me! Tell
me! Oh, watch out, watch out!
Tell me, I got you! Tell me!
- Why karate?
- I want to be strong.
Like the mother
who rescued the dog,
I want to be strong too.
I want to be a hero.
- Yuta...
- I want to be like my mother.
I'll do my best!
- Yuta.
- It's so tight.
Yuta, Yuta.
- It's so tight, mama.
- I'm sorry.
Yuta, even if you become a hero,
take care of yourself.
Take care of your life.
Take care of yourself.
Mommy is very protective of Yuta.
I'll be watching over you.
Even if mama
can't be seen anymore,
she will always protect Yuta.
Are you okay?
Are you sure? Are you okay?
- I thought you were dead.
- What?
I thought mom is dead,
but I was wrong! Mommy is alive.
She is alive. Thank God!
Yuta,
I will tell papa
that mama is alive!
She will always and forever be here.
So I'll be fine!
I'm fine!
Toya!
Thank you, my dear.
Thank you, Yuta.
I love you.
Good to see him.
I'm so happy.
My life has been happy.
Truly, you are not a reaper.
Where did you get that rule from?
We didn't have any proof,
but if that is the case,
We might be able to meet
those who know were dead.
Yes.
This is as far as I can take you.
Now the last door.
Your life is about to be reborn.
May your life be a better one.
Thank you, guide.
Goodbye.
RAW PROVIDER   @hikaririders
TRANSLATION TOOL   DeepL
OFFICIAL SOUNDTRACK
"Sayonara no nai sekai" by Ohashi Trio.
ENGLISH SUBTITLES PROVIDER
Chriz Kayriko