It's me.
That is me, right?
Yes.
I had a liver problem.
I was hospitalized.
Yes.
Dead.
You have understood your situation.
Who are you?
I'm the guide.
Guide? Huh?
- Where are we?
- This is the other side of goodbye.
What? What's that?
- The other side of goodbye...
- Hirokazu.
Hirokazu.
Oh no, why are
you? You!
You! You haven't
met with your father yet!
You didn't contacted him.
Excuse me.
Mrs. Yamawaki, this is his belongings.
How did you get our contact information?
He don't have any relatives.
I got the address
from his belongings.
About the last meeting,
I will explain.
The time left is 24 hours.
Who is the last person you want to see?
GOODBYE MY DEAR
There is no one.
Nobody?
You know what? All of them,
if they think I'm dead,
they'll be wrong.
I'm sure there are people who like me dead.
It's not unusual at all.
They are happy about your death?
EPISODE 2 : THE PRODIGAL SON
Photographs like this,
he must have kept it very dearly.
The other family members,
they're dead.
I thought your father was alive and well.
I don't know.
The last meeting
has some conditions.
The persons who know that you're dead,
you cannot meet them.
If you meet someone who knows you are dead,
at that moment,
you will disappear.
You will be returned here.
So you cannot choose your
sister as your reunion partner
but the other family members and
- some of your friends.
- Yes, Aunt,
Hirokazu has passed away.
I contacted Hirokazu's
classmate from high school.
Listen, the eldest son
of Kamorin liquor store,
she's taking over now. Oh yeah,
the girl called Kamo-chan.
Yeah, she said she'll pass it around.
Will you call all the relatives?
I want to give her a proper
send-off at least at the end.
They're not going to change, sis.
But if it's your father,
you can meet him.
I told you I'm not going.
I've decided that I'm not going
back to my parents' house.
My father has forgotten what I look like.
Dad?
Why aren't you answering the phone?
I told you to put the phone on your side.
Hirokazu passed away.
I guess the whole
world knows I'm dead.
Nevermind.
I told you, there's no one I
want to meet in the first place.
Think again.
You are persistent.
I don't want you to regret it.
I don't care if I have
one or two more regrets.
You shouldn't have any regrets
to take with you to the afterlife.
The less is better, of course.
Okay, okay.
I know.
Thank you very much for visiting us.
NOTICE OF CLOSURE
Thank you very much. We sincerely
apologize for the inconvenience.
This trip...
Yeah! I love you!
I...
What is it?
No...
What are you doing?
You're peeling it off without permission?
Oh no...
- The character is wrong.
- What?
It says "this trip".
Oh...
- I thought you'd better fix it.
- Oh, that's great.
- and...
- What?
I have a DVD that I left on loan.
Finally, I came to return it.
Space Monster Series.
Hahy! Yoo-hoo!
- How much is the late fee?
- Oh, that's fine...that's fine!
- That's not possible.
- No, no, no...
I've been told to get rid of the inventory.
- Did this place go out of business?
- Well, it looks like it.
I'm a part-timer, so I
don't know what's going on.
- What do you want to do?
- What do you mean?
You'll borrow something again,
right? That's what
you always did.
You remember me?
In an age when more and
more people are watching online,
it's very rare to
be our customer.
It would be easier if
you rent them all at once.
Borrowing all at once...
The final series,
I put it in here a while ago.
I put it here!
- Okay, that's enough.
- No...
I know everything.
You know?
- Because I've watched it.
- You have watched all?
I was rewatching
them one at a time.
- I understand!
- No, you're lying.
No, I understand!
You're cherishing what you like.
One at a time,
you feel like you want to review it?
- Because I like them too! Space monsters.
- What?
I think my father liked
that kind of monsters.
Well, he is dead now.
Oh, seriously!
The final series,
please take it with you.
You don't have to return it.
Okay, that's okay.
Because of death?
The space monster,
it's going to die, isn't it?
- In the final version.
- Yes...
Well, it's about to die.
It's so sad.
You don't want to see it.
I also wanted the space
monster to be eternal.
You really like it, don't you?
How about you?
With my father,
we watched it together in the movies.
Me too, me too!
Me too! With my
dad when I was a kid!
Oh, my gosh! Aahahahaha!
Oh, seriously, seriously!
Please take it home with you.
I'll find it right away!
Please wait a minute.
Huh? There it is!
No, no, no...
No, it's around here somewhere.
It's right here! Here we go!
Hirokazu-san's father also
liked movies, didn't he?
You know, my father...
it's gross.
Please stop saying that.
He's a craftsman, aren't he?
Do you know?
I have some information about
the person who is in here.
So you knew that I
left the house?
You wanted to be an actor, right?
Huh, I just aspired to it.
I'm done with it.
- What about your father?
- He didn't say something.
My father was
an old-fashioned craftsman.
He left the house to my mother.
He have never been to my
class or to an athletic meet.
But, he did take you
to the movies, didn't he?
Once every two or three months.
Just a whim or an idea.
I guess he just wanted to go.
I found a figure of a
space monster at the store.
I wanted that.
Goods for sale at the entrance.
Hirokazu, for you.
Thank you!
But my dad bought me,
a caramel.
There is still time.
Time?
Time left for you.
I'm going to have a drink then.
- Yes?
- Let's have a drink?
- What are you talking about?
- Let's have a drink.
I'd love to have one last
drink to soak up the last of it.
You're going to cheat
like that until the end?
Isn't that why you have a bad liver?
Are you trying to tell me that
that is the reason why I died?
No, I'm not.
You know what, they say
"Drinking is the best of all medicines."
I am not talking about alcohol.
You're just trying to
fake your true feelings.
You're running away
from confronting yourself.
Do you really want to
end your life with that?
Enough!
What's wrong with cheating!
What's wrong with running away!
That's what life is all about!
I don't care what kind of life you have.
If that's what you want to do.
- I said enough!
- It's not okay!
You know it's not good!
What the hell is wrong with you!
I am the guide who will
see you through to the end.
Hirokazu Yamawaki,
you cannot return to this world again.
You will never hear their voices again.
You wil never see their faces.
To whom you really want to meet,
lastly, just a glance.
My dad is looking good.
Oh no, hide quickly.
Welcome back.
Let's finish it today,
Isn't that what you used to say, dad?
- We'll get in trouble.
- What? You could've seen me...
"I don't want to be like you dad."
That's what Hirokazu said to me.
I don't know when I started to
look like his father.
You call me... your father?
He said he's an actor.
- What do you mean?
That boy's play,
Yuriko said let's go see it.
I don't know if we can go all the way
to Tokyo. She said we must go.
Dad?
Dad!
Dad.
Where is my father?
By "my father," do you mean my grandfather?
Did you dream again?
The other day, my grandma
came out the other day.
You know, everyone is not here.
Perhaps he has dementia?
Kamo-chan is going to be
the receptionist for the funeral.
Kamo-chan, you know what I mean?
I know Kamo,
but who is dead?
Huh, Hirokazu died!
You said you understood this morning.
So you said you wanted something.
You asked for this, didn't you?
You said you're going
to put it in the hearse.
Do you understand? Do you remember?
He had a bad liver and died.
The wake just finished.
The funeral is in tomorrow.
The funeral director is waiting.
I'm going.
I left it here.
Are you all right?
What the hell are you doing?
Don't leave your tools out!
Put it away!
- Dad...
- What the hell.
I heard Hirokazu passed away.
Don't be stupid!
- But...
- Well then...
Hirokazu who is still
alive today is a ghost!
He is still alive and well.
It's true.
That guy, he's on his
way to becoming an actor.
He's the one who can't come back.
He doesn't have a face to show to you.
That's all.
You, you used to take him to the cinema.
In the truck, you gave Hirokazu a ride.
After that, Hirokazu
knew what a movie is.
He wanted to go to the
other side of the screen.
He is sure out to your
favorite movie world.
He is about to surprise you!
You're an idiot, you know.
You know what makes him think that?
You're the one who's doing the work.
The only time you spent with him,
only that time you two spent together,
it was like a dream for him.
You probably don't even remember.
What is this?
I couldn't buy him, the space monster.
You made this kind of thing,
Yes.
What the hell is this?
It's the space monster.
Stupid.
I don't want my father to call me an idiot.
What are you crying about?
Thank you.
What are you talking about?
I'm saying this on Hirokazu's behalf.
Thanks!
Then, sorry,
sorry, dad.
What are you apologizing for?
Shut up.
Here.
You've taken care of me.
I'm sorry.
No,
I didn't want you to have regrets, like me.
♪ Inochi no honoo
yoru kaze ni sotto kiete ♪
You too have any regrets?
There is no such thing as
a person without regrets.
Hahahaha, maybe.
♪ Kigi wa watashi wo
yasashiku dakishimeru ♪
This is as far as I can take you.
I wonder if I can be reborn.
What kind of person do you want to be next?
Well, I want to be an honest person.
♪ Sayonara ienai ♪
That's how if you can answer honestly.
♪ Itooshi sugita hibi ♪
I think you are already an honest person.
♪ Moshi mata meguriaetara ♪
I'm just an asshole prodigal son.
♪ Sayonara no nai sekai ♪
♪ Kanashimi nanka nai sekai ni ♪
"Sayonara no nai sekai" by Ohashi Tro
RAW AND JP SUBS PROVIDER
@hikaririders
TRANSLATION TOOL
DeepL
ENGLISH SUBTITLES
Chriz Kayriko
THIS DRAMA IS FICTION.