I want to sing.
- Sing?
- Yes.
Um... Who is the last
person you want to see?
I know!
Are you sure you
understand? This place is...
The other side of sadness.
This is other side of goodbye.
I said it on purpose, hehe.
- Kagura Misaki-san, you are...
- I'm dead.
I know, I know.
From a very young age, your heart...
I had a chronic disease.
- And your parents...
- They passed away when I was little.
- I'm one of those lonely people.
- But
you have friends and relatives.
Yes, I have a surrogate parent
and an aunt and uncle who raised me,
also cousins and of course, I have friends.
For example, is there anyone
that you would like to meet from them?
I want to sing!
I want to sing a song
I wrote with Okura.
Okura?
Shinobu Okura.
I want to sing with him.
- There is one rule.
- A rule?
To those who know that
Misaki-san passed away,
you can't meet them.
Eh?
Misaki!
I'm sorry to hear that Okura-san
knows you passed away,
you know, don't you?
If you meet someone who
knows that you're dead,
at that moment
you will disappear,
and you will be back here.
So then I'm not going to see Okura.
- I can't even sing with him.
- Unfortunately,
as long as you are Misaki Kagura.
Hmm?
As long as I am me?
I don't know if this will work.
- It's always been that way.
- When did I say it did?
I mean it will always go wrong,
it's my life so far,
but at least for the last time,
I will definitely do well.
I can only watch and pray.
I'm praying for you.
- Ok!
- Time limit is 24 hours.
- So that means tomorrow?
- Yes, that's right.
- Time limit is on tomorrow,
- 8:00 P.M.
All right! I'm off!
GOODBYE MY DEAR
EPISODE 3 : THE OTHER SIDE OF GOODBYE
- This is Kagura who made a reservation.
- Welcome.
- Like this! Please.
- Yes, ma'am.
Okura and I were classmates
in junior high school.
I never talked to Okura at school.
Welcome!
Wow, this is a gexibe, isn't it?
Oh, in this store,
I'm just helping out.
Our school doesn't allow part-time
work, right? Don't tell this to anyone.
I didn't even paid attention to it.
I was not aware of he's existence at all.
I didn't know what his
interests were at first.
He knew a lot about music.
I started talking with him frequently.
Then we started to see each other.
I didn't feel like we were dating.
After sometime,
he've written an original song.
Amazing, Okura!
Okura's song was amazing.
Because of my heart disease,
in the physical education class,
I had never participated in it before but I
ran seriously for the first time.
I shouldn't get excited about my body.
That guy is so talented.
I really ran for it.
I've never felt like this before.
I have an urge to start running.
I couldn't resist.
Okura, wait!
Your legs are fast.
I wrote a poem with Okura's help.
Since I was born until now,
it was the most exciting time.
I made it again and again and again.
I had to rebuild it about 100 times.
The first song, I was able to do it well.
We were singing the song
that we had written together.
I felt like I could grow wings on my back.
I felt like I could fly.
Me and Okura formed a
unit called "Pay-Per-Back".
Okura writes several songs a month.
I wrote a lot of poems desperately,
and six months later,
I met a guy at my part-time job,
We were invited to join a band.
The day came when we stood
in a live house for the first time.
I'm so nervous.
I heard that you write the character
for "person" on your hand and swallow it.
He's doing it!
I lost the rhythm in my heart.
Misaki,
after today's show,
I have something important to tell you.
What? What did you say?
But that's not the point.
I wonder what he has to say.
We could have sung
in front of a lot of people.
My life doesn't always go well.
Misaki? Misaki
So,
I'll make sure at least at the end,
I'll make it work!
Um...
- Yes.
- I...
Oh, no! I haven't thought about
what I'm going to say.
I'm Misaki's cousin.
You are Okura-san of "Pay-Per-Back", right?
Misaki's cousin?
Don't look at me like that.
You're embarrassing me!
- Hey! Don't look at me like that!
- It hurts. It hurts.
She didn't tell you the details of
her illness. She said she was sorry.
I'm the one who should be sorry,
I'm sorry too.
If I'd known,
in the live or something,
I would have told her not to do it.
What are you talking about?
She wanted to do it!
I mean, to sing.
She said she loves
to sing with Okura-san.
And my story too?
There's no one at school
that you get along with.
You must have been
in despair every day.
She said, "Okura makes great songs".
She always said that.
Misaki was told she might
not live until 5 years old.
Thanks to the medication,
she was able to live until 18.
She says it's like a miracle.
After the age of five,
she thought it was a bonus life.
She didn't expect that she would
meet Okura and form a unit.
It's impossible.
Oh, the Pay-Per-Back song,
it's good.
I had a chance to listen to it.
She was very grateful to Okura-san.
Misaki said she is
glad to have met Okura.
I wish I had never met her.
What?
I'm sorry,
I didn't mean to say this.
Would you like to do a
Pay-Per-Back live with me?
I'm not so bad when you look at it.
I've been told we have similar voices.
And at singing, I know her
because I used to listen to her a lot.
I can sing for Misaki.
You?
For just one day only.
Okura-san and she couldn't do it.
The Pay-per-back live,
would you like to try?
And if we do that, we'll get over it?
Do you think that way?
- It's that easy...
- Are you going to despair again?
You closed the shutters of your mind.
Aren't you an idiot?
Oh, yeah, so you're
back to being alone again?
I want you to continue
the music you started.
No matter how hard it is,
no matter how painful,
to music or song,
there must be a power to overcome it.
If Misaki were alive,
I think she would say that.
Okura.
♪ Don't have to say it ♪
♪ Move on from Sadness Syndrome ♪
♪ Looking down as always ♪
♪ Sooner or later, the
neck is going to fall off ♪
♪ You always have to look back ♪
♪ There is no future ♪
♪ No interest in tomorrow ♪
♪ This makes me wonder
how you spend your time ♪
Yo!
- A song?
- Yeah, I'll do it for Misaki.
What is the theme?
Theme, you know,
in the middle of a dream.
In the middle of a dream?
Yes, in the middle of a dream.
I liked it.
The way you're so absorbed in
writing songs, I loved that image of you.
I really loved it.
This is the last song I wrote.
I will leave a song for him!
- The time limit is on tomorrow,
- 8:00 P.M.
Let's do it then.
I think we should wait a little longer...
It doesn't matter if there
is not enough people.
Misaki would say that.
Yes, Misaki would surely say that.
Just being able to sing
next to Okura is OK!
OK!
♪ How to live well as an adult ♪
♪ There's a trick to it ♪
♪ Don't be afraid of what people think,
Don't challenge them, just give up ♪
♪ These three articles
Can't stand it! ♪
♪ Getting tired of it
Hey, Doc ♪
♪ Falling for someone else's agenda ♪
♪ It's so boring ♪
♪ Everybody ends but they
can't take anything with them ♪
♪ That's why, that's why,
Don't want to have any regrets ♪
♪ Don't want to regret it ♪
♪ Don't worry about anything ♪
♪ The finest runner-up ♪
♪ So, you got me ♪
♪ So, you got me feeling ♪
♪ la la la
You got me feeling ♪
♪ I saw you ♪
♪ Saw the rest of the
dream on the other side ♪
♪ Hey Darling
Let's start again ♪
♪ How to live well as an adult ♪
♪ There's a trick to it ♪
♪ It's not that hard
Don't have to think about it ♪
♪ How about a meal?
Let's have dinner ♪
Okura!
Hurry up! Hey, come here!
What?
- What? What's wrong?
- I wanted to ask you something.
When Misaki collapsed,
what were you going to say?
What?
You wanted to talk to her
about something important.
How did you know about that?
- Miki?
- I don't have time! Please hurry.
I, I..
I'm sure you'll laugh at me.
Go on.
I was going to propose to Misaki.
We haven't even started dating yet.
After the concert was
over I was going to propose.
It's stupid, really.
- That's not true.
- No...
I think Misaki would say I'm an idiot.
She won't say it.
Misaki wouldn't say that.
You don't understand at all.
Let me tell you on behalf of Misaki.
I want you to tell me.
Okay, well, close your eyes.
Okay? I'm taking Misaki's place.
Yes.
It's the reply to your proposal.
Misaki... she says nothing.
She doesn't say anything but she hugs you.
She embraces you with all her strength,
and she kisses you.
Okura!
Keep the music coming.
Keep going. Absolutely.
Okura's music,
it makes people stronger.
Misaki!
I'm glad I met you.
Me too.
Thank you, bye.
Misaki...
Me too...
Welcome back.
I wanted to live more.
I didn't want to die yet.
You wanted to sing with him.
I think your hope was fulfilled.
Yes, but I don't know if
it made sense in the end.
Did you heard his last words?
Huh?
Okura's last words...
Me too...
"Me too, it was good to see you."
He said, "It was good to see you."
Thank you and goodbye.
I love you.
Seriously... that's bad.
Truly that's bad.
Ah! It worked!
My life finally went so well.
Even if it didn't go well,
good or bad,
I have to take it all in.
Oh no, my life has been wonderful.
It's wonderful.
You can say that, Misaki-san,
but you are wonderful too.
That's it.
It's about time.
Misaki's song will
will continue to remain.
Misaki-san's dream is
still in the middle of the road.
I am sure that Okura-san will
continue to walk the rest of the way.
I'll see him again sometime.
I hope you can meet.
Guide-san, good to see you too.
Thank you. Thanks for your time.
JP SUBS AND RAW PROVIDER
@hikaririders
TRANSLATION TOOL
DeepL
OFFICIAL SOUNDTRACK
"Sayonara No Nai Sekai" by Ohashi Trio
ENGLISH SUBTITLES
Chriz Kayriko (@chrizkayriko)
THIS DRAMA IS FICTION