Let's see...
Where was I going to go?
Who is the last person you want to see?
I'm asking you, Taniguchi-san.
Um, excuse me...
I am your guide to the last door.
I was going to buy
some leeks for a sukiyaki.
Oh, green onions...
No, it's more difficult
than that, Taniguchi-san.
Taniguchi-san, you're already dead.
Yes?
You are dead.
Yoko?
Yoko-san is the wife
of Taniguchi-san, right?
Do you know her?
I know the general
information of who will be here.
The two of you met two years ago,
April 10, 1982.
You were going to deliver
mail at a barbershop, right?
How do you know that?
The previous owner passed away there and
there was no one using the
store for a while, wasn't it?
Yes, that's right.
That place has...
Oh...
A nice woman has started working there.
Yes, that was our first meeting of Yoko.
I don't even remember what she said.
When she saw me, I thought my
heart was going to jump out of my mouth.
I've never seen anything
like this before in my life.
And then, even when
it's not my delivery time,
I started going to her barber shop.
Somewhere along the way, she started
referring to me as not "the mailman".
She started calling me "Taniguchi-san".
We became husband and wife.
We rented a house with a small garden.
We planted a plum tree in the garden.
Then with one little dog,
we did not want children.
Yoko always made sukiyaki on my payday.
For me, it was a dreamy time.
I thought if I woke up, it would disappear,
there was a time when I thought that.
That day was both payday
and our wedding anniversary.
She realized that she forgot
to buy leeks at the supermarket.
It was a special day.
I wanted to go home as soon as possible.
But I felt dizzy,
the ground became distorted and
I couldn't stand up.
It was an indescribable feeling.
It's stroke.
I see, I'm dead.
But you know what, Taniguchi-san?
I have something for you.
There is one remaining hope.
Hope?
One last day,
to the people you want to see in this life,
you can go to see them.
So then,
I can go see Yoko, right?
Uh, I'm sorry to tell you this,
I'm afraid you can't do that.
Why not?
From now on, the only people
Tanaguchi-san can see are
the only people who
don't know that you died.
Well then, Yoko...
Yoko already mourned.
Your funeral has been completed.
Therefore, your relatives who
attended and those at work....
It's just Yoko.
She's the only one I want to see!
That's the rule.
She changed my life.
Yoko is my life!
She's everything in my life!
Please, let me see Yoko.
Let me see Yoko!
Well, even if you put it that way,
I'm still planning something,
I haven't told her anything important.
We're in trouble.
GOODBYE MY DEAR
episode 4 : A Long Time
Sayaka is the only one I want to see.
Hey, are you listening?
Excuse me,
I was just thinking.
Please! This kind of place,
I can't use this.
Kotaro Iseya,
unfortunately,
You may only meet those
who don't know you died.
- That's a rule.
- Then, I told you earlier!
We had a fight over
something boring and I ran out.
Sayaka still doesn't know
about the accident.
Oh, it seems so.
Then,
here you go.
What is wrong?
Kotaro-san?
I think it's okay.
You and Sayaka-san,
you lived together, right?
Yes.
The life with the two of you
must have been fun, huh?
Every day is a great day.
That's... happiness is happy.
- If that's the case, then right now...
- Sayaka is, you know, a crybaby.
She's a crybaby and sensitive.
If I meet her halfway,
I might make her sad even more.
I want to see her but
I don't want to see her.
I see.
I can't stay by her side all the time.
I wonder if there is any
meaning in seeing her.
Kotaro! Kotaro!
Kotaro!
It looks like a place of
memories for the two of you.
She enjoys photography.
I'm surprised she came
here to take pictures.
I've been modeled for a long time.
I see.
Sayaka's pics are so sweet,
like a small flower blooming
on the side of the road,
discarded and lying around
that they were thrown away,
cutting out a small world that no one sees.
Please go to her, Kotaro-san.
Why are you such a pest?
It may be difficult for you.
It's hard to tell it to your loved ones.
But to touch each other
and feel the warmth,
you are still allowed to have that time.
Kotaro.
Hi.
Thank God!
I was so worried.
Thank goodness.
Don't go anywhere else, Kotaro.
I knew I made you cry.
I'm sorry, Sayaka,
I have to go now.
Running away, ah you caught it.
Ohh, let go of it, let it go.
Kotaro, this way, this way...
I was really happy to live with Sayaka.
Every day that we spent together,
I will never forget it.
I love her more than anything in the world.
Kotaro...
Thanks.
Thanks to you,
I got it right at the end.
I got to tell her how much I love her.
Happiness is happy.
Kotaro-san, it's because
you had courage.
I, even if I'm born again,
I'm going to be Sayaka's cat.
I hope that day will come.
I got tell her how much I love her.
How's it going?
We've known each other for a long time.
You've been here for 10 years now.
No matter what you say,
I only want to see Yoko.
You're a really strange person.
Normally you wouldn't be able to stand
such an unbearable hell.
I can spend my life
here thinking about Yoko.
I thought maybe it's not so bad,
yeah, this kind of life
thing, don't you call it?
Life, huh?
I came here today with a proposal.
Proposal?
Taniguchi-san,
would you like to be the guide?
What?
Now, it's about time I leave.
I think it's time for me
to have a reincarnation.
But can I play such a big role?
If you're patient, you're perfect for it.
You will have to wait here, though.
That's fine,
I'll be here anyway.
I'm not sure if you're a
laid-back person or what,
Taniguchi-san,
you may be suited to be the guide.
I'm sure you're suited for it.
I'm sure you'll be able to see them off.
I'm going now.
Thank you, guide.
What the hell are you!
You took care of me.
I'm sorry.
Guide-san, it was nice to meet you too.
Thank you, good work.
I'm glad I apologized,
thanks to you guide.
Thank you!
Yoko...
Kenji-san...
Kenji-san, is that you?
Yoko...
It's like a dream.
It really is Yoko, isn't it?
All I do is to grow so old.
You didn't change, until now.
On the other side of goodbye?
I am called "the guide".
I didn't know there was a world like this.
It's been a really long time.
I'm sorry to keep you waiting.
I don't mind waiting.
Me too,
there's something I really
wanted to say to Yoko.
For always cutting my hair, thank you.
For making my favorite
miso soup, thank you.
For keeping my beer cold, thank you.
And then,
then,
For being with me, thank you.
You made my life bright.
I really love your smile.
Always, always,
always and ever,
I only love you.
Kenji-san...
Ahh... I could finally say it.
It's such a simple thing.
Why couldn't I have said it
honestly while I was alive?
It's nice to have it put into words.
I'm glad to hear you say it.
Then,
if we are born again,
let's get married.
Of course.
I know it's late, but
I'm back, Yoko.
Welcome back, Kenji-san.
Thank you for the happy hour.
Thank you, too.
I've been waiting for you here
for a long time. I'm really glad.
I'm glad you'll be seeing me off, too.
Let's meet again someday.
Someday,
certainly.
OFFICIAL SOUNDTRACK
"Sayonara no nai sekai" by Ohashi Trio
RAW AND JP SUBS PROVIDER
@hikaririders
TRANSLATION TOOL
DeepL
ENGLISH SUBTITLES
Chriz Kayriko (@chrizkayriko)
Who is the last person you want to see?
THIS DRAMA IS FICTION
HULU ORIGINAL STORY WILL BE RELEASED!
You want to go to the
person you love the most,
- it's what you wish for, isn't it?
- Mom, dad,
NO!!!
- I want to get married.
- Yes.
Dear Yoko,
I can't imagine my life without you.
Will you continue to cut my hair?
After this,
the streaming starts on HULU!