"SHOWA KAYO MUSICAL"
"1988"
ARE YOU OKAY?
I HAVE RETURNED TO THE SHOWA ERA
I'VE ALWAYS WISHED
I COULD GO TO A DIFFERENT TIME
I HAVE ARRIVED AT A DISTANT FUTURE.
REIWA?
- WHAT IS REIWA?   - WHAT?
- WHAT?   - WHEN IS THIS PLACE... HERE?
WHERE AM I?
GOOD MORNING!
MOTHER... OUCH!
YOU... HUSBAND?
EH?
YOU'RE MY HUSBAND!
I WENT OUT WITH HIM.
AND I FOUND MYSELF IN A STRANGE WORLD.
A CALM, GENTLE, DREAMLIKE TIME.
BUT...
SO, YOU DON'T WANT TO BE A WRITER?
I HAVE MORE IMPORTANT THINGS TO DO
THAN SELL AND MAKE MONEY.
THAT'S A LIE.
THIS IS THE STORY OF MY GREAT ADVENTURE
"SHOWA KAYO MUSICAL
MATA AU HI MADE"
AH~! IRASSHAI~.
BEFORE LEAVING ON A JOURNEY INTO THE FUTURE,
I WAS SINGING AT MY PARENTS' SNACK BAR
THAT'S GOOD~.
- MOTHER~ WATER~
- YES, MA'AM.
OH... OH... OH... OH.
OH, SAE-CHAN.
I'M GLAD YOU'RE HERE MOMOE.
UEKI-SAN, YOU WERE SLEEPING.
500 YEN FOR THE REQUEST.
I WAS BATHING WITH MY BODY.
OH, SAE. TO YAMAOKA-SAN.
HA~Y.
- MR. YAMAOKA
- OH, I'VE BEEN WAITING, WAITING.
THAT WAS GOOD.
THE CHOICE OF MUSIC WAS EXCELLENT.
- THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
- I WAS SO IMPRESSED.
YES, I'LL SING ANYTHING YOU WANT
FOR 500 YEN PER SONG. I'LL SING ANYTHING.
SAE-CHAN, HOW DID IT GO?
THE AUDITION THE OTHER DAY.
- SHE LEFT IN THE MIDDLE OF THE SHOW.
- WHY AGAIN?
I HEARD THAT SHE SAID
DURING THE INTERVIEW,
"I DON'T LIKE SONGS. I HATE SONGS!"
OH, NO! WHY DID SHE SAID THAT?
SHE LOVE SONGS, DON'T SHE?
SHE'S NOT BEING HONEST.
OH, IT'S ME! IT'S ME!
MIFUNE-CHAN, WAIT.
OKAY, OKAY, I'M GOING.
TODAY SOMEONE IS INTOXICATED BY SONG
AND THE SONG HEALS AND FILLS THEM.
SONGS ARE FOR EVERYONE.
BUT TO ME, IT'S JUST CRAP.
MY FATHER WAS A LYRICIST WHO
WROTE SONGS THAT DIDN'T SELL.
LIVING ONLY FOR HIS OWN DREAMS...
AND THEN HE DIED.
HATE...
I HATE SONGS AND THIS ERA...
AND MYSELF BURIED HERE...
AUDITION, SINGER CATEGORY.
PASSED THE FIRST ROUND!
- YOU PASSED!
- YES!
- OH MY GOD~ I'M SO SICK OF IT.
- WHY?
I'M NOT GOING TO TAKE THE SECOND ROUND
ANYWAY, AND I'M NOT INTERESTED IN IT.
HMMM... I GUESS THAT'S THE USUAL.
SAE-SAN, YOU CAN BE A SINGER.
YES, YES. GANBA RUMBA!
GANBA RUMBA!
- HEY~ SOY SAUCE FACE
- I'M NOT SURE IF THAT'S TRUE OR NOT.
WHAT? YES!
ISONO-SAN, LEAVE IT ON MY DESK.
IT'S TOO HEAVY TO BRING TO SALES.
NO, DO IT YOURSELF...
IT'S A GIRL'S JOB, RIGHT?
WE'RE THE ONES WHO MAKE THE MONEY.
WHY DO I HAVE TO...
WELL THEN, NICE TO MEET YOU!
- DON'T MIND
WHAT'S WRONG?
MIURA-SAN.
YOU GUYS, WHEN A 5'9" LIKE ME.
I CAN SEE THE INSIDE JOB AT HAND.
OH, MY GOD.
OH, NO!
FUTURE STARS WANTED...
PASSED THE SCREENING PROCESS.
IT'S TRUE.
SAE-CHAN IS AIMING TO BE A SINGER.
NO... THIS KIND OF THING
DOESN'T MATTER ANYMORE.
MY MOTHER IS SENDING IT TO ME ON HER OWN.
I TOLD HER I WAS INTERESTED IN IT
FOR A LITTLE WHILE A LONG TIME AGO.
I'M GOING TO BE YANKEE, AREN'T I?
HOW ABOUT THE FUTURE OVER HERE?
"BACK TO THE FUTURE" ADVANCE TICKETS?
WAIT FOR ME OUTSIDE THE OFFICE AFTER WORK.
I BOUGHT A NEW CAR.
LET'S GO FOR A DRIVE.
OKAY.
I'LL TAKE THIS ONE.
CIAO.
SO COOL~!
YOU'RE LEAVING ON YOUR OWN
TERMS WITHOUT ME?
YOU ARE QUICK-TEMPERED. BESIDES, I WANT
TO WORK EVEN IF I'M MARRIED.
YOU KNOW, IF YOU GET
MARRIED AND STAY IN THE
COMPANY, YOU'RE NOT
GOING TO BE ABLE TO WORK.
HIGHLY EDUCATED, HIGH INCOME, HIGH HEIGHT.
IF IT'S MIURA-SAN, A THREE-TALENTED MAN...
I HAVE NO COMPLAINTS~.
HE'S BEING PRAISED AGAIN.
HEY, WE'RE ALL GOING OUT FOR A DRINK TODAY.
THIS MONTH, MIURA IS THE TOP SALESMAN.
IT'S A PRE-PROMOTION CELEBRATION FOR SURE.
I'M SORRY, I'M A LITTLE BUSY TODAY.
WHAT'S THAT?
YOU TURNED ME DOWN YESTERDAY TOO, RIGHT?
I HAD TO PICK UP MY CHILD.
YOU'RE SO COLD. IF YOU CARE ABOUT YOUR
CHILD, WHY DON'T YOU JUST BE A HOUSEWIFE?
I'M SORRY.
- RIGHT? HE HAVE NARROW SHOULDERS.
- HMM?
I'M NOT GOING EITHER.
HUH? ISONO, YOU'RE SINGLE.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
I DON'T HAVE THE GUTS TO HECKLE MY BOSS.
WHO ARE YOU TALKING TO?
TO A BOSS WHO DOESN'T UNDERSTAND.
HEY, SAE.
WHAT, WHAT~...
YOU'D BETTER WATCH HOW YOU TALK OR
YOU WON'T BE ABLE TO STAY IN THE COMPANY.
YOU CAN'T EVEN GET MARRIED.
IS IT POSSIBLE THAT TODAY
IS THE DAY, ISONO?
OUCH! DID YOU HIT ME?
- I DIDN'T HIT YOU.
- YOU HIT ME!
SHE HIT ME, DIDN'T SHE?
THERE'S NO NEED TO HIT ANYTHING.
THE BOSS WAS VERY ANGRY. IF YOU DO
A BAD JOB, YOU'LL BE FIRED FOR SOME REASON.
I DON'T CARE IF IT'S
A TEMPORARY JOB.
BUT IF YOU'RE GOING TO
WORK, YOU HAVE TO DO IT RIGHT.
I'M WORKING!
ISONO-SAN... DON'T DO ANYTHING UNNECESSARY.
EH?
BECAUSE IT WOULD MAKE MY POSITION WORSE.
I HAVE TO GO PICK MY CHILD UP.
- ANYWAY, I'M GOING TOO.
- WHAT ABOUT THE MOVIE?
I HAVE TO GO WITH THE DIRECTOR AT LEAST.
GO TO THE MOVIES WITH SOMEONE.
KEEP SMILING. WOMEN ARE CHARMING.
I'M HUNGRY.
WHERE DO YOU WANT TO GO?
WHAT DO YOU RECOMMEND?
WE'RE GOING TO EAT AT A RESTAURANT.
"SNACK BAR
THE ARK"
- WAKA, I WAS BORN IN THE WRONG ERA.
- WHAT? YOU WANT EDO OR MEIJI?
WRONG! A KINDER, LESS HAWKEN-ESQUE ERA.
NOT THE PAST, MORE THE FUTURE!
YOU LIKE THE FUTURE.
INFLUENCE OF THE MOVIE?
HAVE YOU EVER THOUGHT ABOUT IT? IF ONLY
THERE WAS A BETTER FUTURE TO LIVE IN.
HMMM...
I DON'T FIT IN THIS TIME PERIOD.
SOCIETY, TRENDS, THE WAY
PEOPLE THINK, AND MUSIC.
COME ON, DON'T BE ROTTEN,
LET'S GO DANCING!
I MET A GUY THE OTHER DAY. HE SAID HE'D
TAKE ME TO A NEW DISCO IN SHIBAURA.
OH, IT'S ME, IT'S ME!
SAE-CHAN, SAE-CHAN.
SAE! REQUEST.
AIYO.
SORRY.
I LIKE THIS ERA. BYE-BYE~.
BYE BYE~.
AH~!
SAE, AREN'T YOU DRINKING A LITTLE TOO MUCH?
IF I DON'T DRINK,
I CAN'T SING "LONELY CHAPLIN" ELEVEN TIMES.
EVERYONE SINGS TOO MANY POPULAR SONGS.
ISN'T THAT GOOD?
YOU CAN FEEL THE SAME WAY.
I'M NOT SURE.
YOU HAVE ANOTHER AUDITION TOMORROW, RIGHT?
ARE YOU GOING TO BE OKAY?
IT'S OKAY. I'M NOT GOING TO GET IT ANYWAY.
I'M NOT GOING TO BE ACCEPTED IN THIS AGE.
- I MIGHT AS WELL TAKE OVER THIS STORE.
- YOU'VE GOT TO BE KIDDING!
IF YOU DO THAT, I'LL HATE YOU.
YOU'LL BE RESENTED BY ME
FOR THE REST OF YOUR LIFE.
BECAUSE OF ME, YOU HAD
TO GIVE UP YOUR DREAM.
I DON'T HATE THAT.
I MEAN, SERIOUSLY. IF YOU REALLY WANT TO
TAKE OVER THIS RESTAURANT, FINE.
BUT IF YOU USE IT AS A REASON
TO GIVE UP ON YOUR DREAM...
EVEN MY MOTHER.
YOU'VE GIVEN UP A LOT, HAVEN'T YOU?
YOU, TO RAISE ME.
WELL, BUT CERTAINLY SOMETHING I LIKE.
I WISH I HAD STUDIED, I GUESS.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO STUDY?
- NOTHING
- MISHU-CHAN, LOOK AT THIS!
WHAT? WHAT?
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT
IT'S THE TIMES. IT'S THE TIMES, EVERYTHING.
IT'S KARA GLASS.
IF YOU LIVED IN A DIFFERENT TIME.
I WONDER IF YOU WOULD HAVE BEEN HAPPY.
YES. DEFINITELY.
THANKS FOR THE BEER.
WEIRD.
THIS CANDY IS "MOSHIMO AME".
WHAT "MOSHIMO AME"?
THIS UNIVERSE IS NOT ONE.
THERE IS A WORLD WHERE YOU RUN A BAKERY.
THERE ARE WORLDS WHERE YOU ARE LIVING IN
THE FAR FUTURE. IT'S A MULTIVERSE THEORY.
YOU LICK THIS CANDY AND WISH, "WHAT
IF THIS WORLD WERE LIKE THIS."
AND THEN YOU TRAVEL TO ONE
OF THE TENS OF THOUSANDS OF WORLDS.
HUH?
THANKS. ARE YOU TRYING TO COMFORT ME?
ARE YOU A TRAVELER?
YOU DON'T LOOK FAMILIAR.
I JUST LIKE TO SING.
I WAS PASSING BY THIS STORE,
AND I HEARD YOU SINGING.
OH, DO YOU HAVE ANY REQUESTS?
I'LL SING TODAY! I WANT TO
SING LOUSILY AND LET IT FLOW.
OKAY, TODAY... YOU'LL SING A SONG
THAT'S RIGHT FOR YOU RIGHT NOW.
- EH~? WHAT IS IT?
- MAY I?
OH WELL.
HOW MUCH DID YOU DRINK?
I'M OKAY, I'M OKAY.
HUH? WHAT'S THIS...
- AH! SAE!
- ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
OH?
HEY... THE MAN
SIR?
HEY... MISTER!
- MISTER?
- SAE!
DID I SLEPT HERE?
OH MY GOD! 8 O'CLOCK!
OH, CAB, CAB, CAB!
QUIET CAR... OH, SORRY.
- JINGU-BASHI 1 TO 23.
- YES.
DA~KA~RA! WHERE ARE WE?
I DON'T KNOW WHERE THIS BIG BUILDING IS!
- THAT'S THE ADDRESS YOU GAVE ME!
- ISN'T THIS SHIMURAYA, THE MEAT BUN SHOP?
SHIMURAYA IS A MUCH SHABBIER BUILDING!
- THIS IS IT!
- NO, IT'S NOT!
WHAT'S HAPPENING WITH HER?
JUST DON'T PAY!
- WHAT? WHAT? WAIT A MINUTE!
- LET GO!
I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU LEFT ME HERE~!
OH MY GOD!
HUH...
WHERE AM I?
- WHAT ARE YOU LOOKING AT?
- WAKA!
GOOD MORNING, SAE. WHAT IS IT?
EIGHTIES STYLE? THAT'S SO FASHIONABLE!
WAKA, YOU TOO.
HOW'S YOUR TOSAKA?
HOW ABOUT AN HOUR'S TOSSER
FOR BLOW-DRYING EVERY MORNING?
HUH? AND YOUR CLOTHES ARE KIND OF PLAIN!
WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
NO, IT'S NORMAL.
COME ON, WE'RE GOING TO BE LATE. LET'S GO.
- WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
- COMPANY.
- WAKA! WAKA! WAKA, WAKA, WAKA!
- WHAT, WHAT, WHAT?
- OH MY GOD! VIDEOPHONE!
- STOP IT.
OH, WAKA... WAKA, WAIT A MINUTE!
WHAT? WHAT? WHAT'S WRONG?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- WHAT IS THIS?
- DID YOU FORGET YOUR EMPLOYEE ID CARD?
SHA... EMPLOYEE ID CARD?
THERE IS.
OH, NO.
LIKE A NEWBORN FAWN...
WE'RE GOING TO GO.
- GOOD MORNING.
- GOOD MORNING, NATSUKI-SAN. ISONO-SAN.
GOOD MORNING...
KAORI-SAN, ARE YOU AT THE BABY'S OFFICE? ALL
THE TIME. I LEAVE THEM IN THE NURSERY.
- NURSERY...
- GOOD MORNING.
- KAEDE-CHAN, GOOD MORNING.
- PLEASE GIVE MY BEST REGARDS.
- YES, WE WILL TAKE CARE OF YOU.
- SEE YOU LATER.
- MOMMY GOT AWAY.
- NURSERY... FOR COMPANY?
WHERE'S THIS PLACE?
NEKUMAN INNOVATION SHIMURAYA.
BUT THE UNIFORMS ARE DIFFERENT.
THE BUILDING IS DIFFERENT.
WORK IS THE SAME.
WE WERE ALL THE SAME.
BUT IT LOOKS LIKE THE FUTURE!
- OH~!
- WHAT?
- WOW~!
- WHAT'S UP? AHAHAHA... WHAT'S THE STORY?
- WHAT?
- OH, NOISY!
- WHAT'S WRONG, SAE?
- A... ROBOT!
WHAT? IT'S OUR GUIDE, ROBO-KUN.
WE'RE WORKING TOGETHER.
- GOOD MORNING.
- HE'S SMILING...
- LET'S DO OUR BEST FOR ANOTHER DAY.
LET'S DO OUR BEST!
BYE BYE.
- EMPLOYEE?
- EMPLOYEE... NOT.
- THIS EXPO? WHAT EXPO?
- HUH?
I MEAN, ISONO-SAN, YOU MUST BE GOING
THROUGH A MENTAL BREAKDOWN
- MENTAL? YES,   - YOU HAVE MENTAL.
- THERE'S THAT.
BUT I'M GLAD YOU SAID IT.
THERE WAS A SEXUAL HARASSER.
SEX...?
THERE IS NO SUCH THING AS FORCED
DRINKING. IT'S POWER HARASSMENT.
POWER?
OUR COMPANY, COMPLIANCE
IS NOT GOOD ENOUGH.
CON...?
WHEN DID THIS HAPPEN?
BUT THANKS TO ISONO-SAN.
THANKS TO YOU.
I'LL SAY IT CLEARLY.
I DON'T THINK HE CAN STAY HERE ANY LONGER.
I'M REALLY SORRY ABOUT THAT.
WHAT? IT WASN'T ME. IT'S THE DIRECTOR!
THE DIRECTOR COULDN'T STAY.
THE DIRECTOR?
SEE, SEE, SEE.
DIRECTOR ISHIBASHI! WE HAVE YOUR DOCUMENTS.
THIS
2022?
OH, ISONO-KUN,
SORRY ABOUT YESTERDAY...
REI... WA 4 YEARS? REIWA?
- WHAT IS "REIWA"?
- WHAT?
WHAT? THIS PLACE IS... WHEN IS THIS PLACE?
WHERE AM I?
OH, THERE'S A PHONE CALL.
- SAE, ISN'T THAT YOUR BAG?
- EH? BAG
- YEAH. SAE, ISN'T IT?
- HMM?
WHAT THE HELL IS THIS?
- YOU'RE NOT GETTING IT?
- WHAT?
- NO ANSWER?
- NOT ANSWERING?
SMART PHONE.
- SMART PHONE?
- SO, THIS ONE. QUICKLY, QUICKLY.
HUH? HUH? HUH?
OH, YOU LOST IT.
WELL, I HOPE THAT'S OK.
- OH, WAA!
- WHAT~?
WHAT IS THIS~!
WHAT? ME? I'M KIND OF CUTE!
I'M CUTE!
- YOU'RE CUTE. YOU SAY SO YOURSELF?
- CUTE~!
UM~ SAE-CHAN.
WHO ARE YOU?
NO, IT'S MIURA.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, MIURA-SAN?
I'M NOT SURE IF IT'S A GOOD IDEA OR NOT.
I'VE ALWAYS BEEN LIKE THIS, HAVEN'T I?
MIURA-KUN HAS ALWAYS BEEN A QUIET,
GOOD-NATURED YOUNG MAN. HE'S LIKE A SHEEP.
EVERYONE IS DIFFERENT FROM USUAL.
WE ALL CAME TO THE FUTURE...
I DON'T THINK SO. AM I THE ONLY ONE
WHO CAME TO THE FUTURE?
NO. WE ALL LIVE HERE IN THE FUTURE.
ANOTHER WORLD?
ARE YOU OKAY?
CAN I GO HOME TODAY?
UMMM... YEAH, THAT'S A GOOD IDEA!
YOU DON'T SEEM TO BE FEELING WELL.
IF YOU WANT.
YOU CAN WORK REMOTELY IF YOU WANT.
- REMOTE?
- YES.
COMMUNICATE REMOTELY...
TELEPATHY...?
WOW! THAT'S A LOT....
WHAT IS THAT... SCARY!
JULIE.... THERE ARE SONGS
FROM THE SHOWA ERA.
- OH, DO YOU WANT ME TO STOP THE MUSIC?
- OH, IT'S FINE.
I'M GLAD THIS IS IT....
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
MOTHER!
PARFAIT.
COFFEE SHOP?
TAPI... CAFE?
- MOTHER... OW!
- OUCH!
I'M SORRY, I'M STILL PREPARING...
OH... WELCOME BACK.
YOU'RE HOME EARLY.
ARE YOU DONE WITH WORK ALREADY?
YOU DIDN'T COME HOME YESTERDAY.
I DON'T MEAN TO NAG YOU, BUT IF
YOU'RE GOING TO STAY OUT OVERNIGHT,
YOU SHOULD TELL ME.
ARE YOU... MY HUSBAND?
WHAT?
YOU'RE MY HUSBAND!
NO... SORRY, I DIDN'T
MEAN IT LIKE THAT.
BUT IF WE'RE GOING TO LIVE
TOGETHER, THERE ARE SOME RULES...
WHAT? LIVING TOGETHER, YOU AND I?
- WHAT ABOUT MY MOTHER?
- OH... UNFORTUNATELY, NOT ANYMORE.
NO WAY...
- SHE'S PROBABLY UP IN THE SKY RIGHT NOW.
- NO WAY...
JUST BECAUSE THE PLANE WON'T
MAKE IT IN TIME... HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY!
HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY... WHAT'S WRONG?
ARE YOU OKAY? HEY! SAE-SAN!
FRANCE... STUDY ABROAD?
YESTERDAY, MIFUNE-SAN SUDDENLY WENT BACK
TO JAPAN TEMPORARILY. HE LEFT THIS MORNING.
SHE WAS WAITING TO SEE YOU, BUT...
SHE DIDN'T CALL YOU?
- PHONE CALL?
- TO YOUR PHONE.
SMA.... OH, PERHAPS....
IS THIS A PHONE?
MAYBE A MONTH LATER.
HE SAID HE'S GOING BACK.
MOTHER. IN THIS DAY AND AGE,
SHE LIVES FREELY.
- HMM?
- I'M SORRY, I SHOULDN'T HAVE SAID THAT.
IN OTHER WORDS, THE SNACK BAR CLOSED
MANY YEARS AGO. AND NOW IT'S A COFFEE SHOP.
- CALL IT A CAFE.
- AND YOU ARE THE MANAGER.
I'M HIRED.
I MEAN... YOU DRANK TOO MUCH ALCOHOL AND
YOU HAVE A TEMPORARY MEMORY LAPSE.
IS IT SOMETHING YOU FORGET LIKE THAT?
I DRANK TOO MUCH YESTERDAY.
BY THE WAY, WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
- REALLY?
- I'LL REMEMBER IT SOON, BUT JUST IN CASE.
NOBI. NOBI NOBORU.
NOBI.
PLAYWRIGHT. I HAVE A THEATER COMPANY
SEPARATE FROM THE CAFÉ.
- OH, THAT'S RIGHT. I REMEMBER NOW.
- THIS IS THE FIRST TIME I'VE SAID THIS.
WHAT? OH... MY MOTHER TOLD ME.
OH, THAT'S RIGHT.
SHE OFTEN COME TO SEE OUR PLAY.
THAT'S WHY
I'VE BEEN INVITED TO THIS CAFE.
WHERE DO YOU LIVE?
- IT'S A STAGE.
- WHAT?
AHHH! THE STAGE...
YOU REALLY LIVE HERE...
I CAN'T BELIEVE A PLAYWRIGHT LIVES ON
STAGE. PHEW... THAT'S A VALUABLE EXPERIENCE.
I DON'T WANT TO DO IT ANYMORE.
A MAN AND A WOMAN WHO DON'T KNOW
EACH OTHER VERY WELL UNDER ONE ROOF?
AFTER ALL THIS TIME?
IT'S JUST A SHARED HOUSE.
- WE'RE NOT EVEN CLOSE.
- IT'S OKAY. I'M A HERBIVORE.
- YOU'RE A HERBIVORE.
- HERBIVORE! I'M A HERBIVORE.
YES. TAPIOCA. YOU WANT SOME?
TAPI... TAPIOCA?
TAPIOCA.
THERE'S SOMETHING IN IT! IN MY MOUTH!
IT LOOKS LIKE A TADPOLE!
WHAT... YOU'VE NEVER EATEN IT BEFORE?
WHAT IS THIS? A CANDY?
IT'S NOT CANDY.
CANDY!
IF YOU LIVED IN A DIFFERENT TIME.
I WONDER IF YOU WOULD HAVE BEEN HAPPY.
YES.
THAT TRAVELER....
OKAY, I'M GOING TO OPEN SOON.
DELICIOUS.
TAPIOCA. DELICIOUS!
SO, CANDY!
- MOSHIMO CANDY!
- MOSHIMO CANDY?
YES! A CANDY THAT MAKES
"WHAT IF" COME TRUE.
BECAUSE OF THAT FUNNY CANDY
I CAME TO A DIFFERENT WORLD.
- BECAUSE I WISHED FOR IT.
- WHAT DID YOU WISH FOR?
IF I LIVED IN THE FUTURE.
THE FUTURE, YOU'RE HERE IN THE PRESENT.
THAT'S NOT IT.
I AM FROM THE SHOWA PERIOD.
- HUH...
- COMPUTERS ARE SO...
- IT WAS THIS BIG.
- HA~N.
WAKA WAS WEARING A BODYCON LIKE THIS
AND WENT TO THE DISCO EVERY NIGHT!
WAIT, DISCOS ARE STILL AROUND?
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING? WHAT DO YOU DO?
- STUDYING FOR A CERTIFICATION?
WAKA? WAKA, THE GIRL WHO WANTS
TO BE THE CENTER OF A BALL, IS STUDYING?
- HEY, "TAMANOKOSHI" IS A DEAD WORD.
- WHAT A BAD TIME WE ARE LIVING IN.
TAPIOCA SOY LATTE MARRON
GRANDE SIZE, TWO FOR YOU.
AND I'M LIVING WITH A GUY. WITH A GUY I
DON'T EVEN KNOW! HE'S THE MANAGER.
SHARED HOUSE WITH A MANAGER?
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- MATCHING APP.
- MATCHING?
- YOU'RE THE ONE...
IT'S LIKE A BLIND DATE. THEY INTRODUCE YOU
TO SOMEONE WHO MATCHES YOUR REQUIREMENTS.
- OH, I GOT A MATCH!
- IS THAT A MATCH?
PIYOMARU, 34 YEARS OLD.
ANNUAL INCOME, 3.4 MILLION.
OCCUPATION: MANUFACTURING.
HOBBIES: READING.
SOBER~! I DON'T WANT TO GO
ON A BLIND DATE LIKE THAT.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT KIND OF BAD
DREAM YOU'RE HAVING.
SHOULDN'T YOU GET OFF YOUR
ASS AND LOOK FOR A TRAVELER?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT KIND OF
BAD DREAM YOU'RE HAVING.
BUT HE JUST WANDERED INTO OUR STORE.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW HIS NAME.
THEN WHY DON'T YOU WAIT
FOR HIM AT THE STORE?
- AT THE STORE?
- YEAH.
GOOD IDEA.
- I CAN'T REALLY PAY YOU, CAN I?
- YES! IT'S A SOCIAL STUDY.
OH, LEAVE THE CUSTOMER SERVICE TO ME.
I'VE DONE ENOUGH IN SNACK BARS.
IN THE MEANTIME, NOBI,
YOU CAN WRITE A SCRIPT OR SOMETHING.
WHAT ABOUT THE COMPANY? ARE YOU OKAY?
NO, I'M FINE. I'M CONNECTED TO THE COMPANY
BY REMOTE. I HEARD THAT IT IS CONNECTED.
- OH... CAN YOU TELL ME LATER?
- OKAY.
OH, AND IF THIS TRAVELER-LOOKING
GUY COMES TO THE STORE...
IF THIS TRAVELER-LIKE PERSON COMES
TO THE STORE, PLEASE BE CAREFUL...
- I SHOULD REPORT IT?
- YES!
BUT I WONDER IF THIS WILL MAKE SENSE.
- EXCUSE ME.
- AH, WELCOME!
- WELCOME!
- THERE ARE TWO OF US.
ARE THERE TWO OF YOU?
PLEASE COME THIS WAY.
OH, THERE ARE TWO OF YOU!
- YES, SIR.
- YES!
MARI... TOTSO...?
SORRY TO KEEP YOU WAITING~!
MA....
- MA.... MATRITUZZO~.
- YES...
- ARE YOU ALONE?
- YES... YES.
DO YOU COME TO THESE PLACES OFTEN?
CLOSE, CLOSE! EXCUSE ME!
MA....
MA!
OH, THE CLOCK IS SO NICE!
I'M INTERESTED IN WATCHES TOO...
SO CLOSE, CLOSE! I'M SORRY.
MARI... TOZZO?
IT IS!
- YES, STRAWBERRY MILK.
- YES.
THANK YOU FOR WAITING.
TAPIOCA STRAWBERRY MILK.
- THANK YOU.
- THANKS.
WHAT, YOU'RE BORED ALREADY?
I'M JUST GOING TO SERVE TAPIOCA.
IT'S NOT A SNACK BAR.
I'VE BEEN AWARE OF IT FOR A WHILE, BUT THE
PEOPLE AT 2022 REALLY LIKE IT, DON'T THEY?
IS THAT?
A SMART PHONE?
WE'RE IN A COFFEE SHOP AND
EVERYONE'S LOOKING AT THEIR SCREENS.
WHAT'S SO IMPORTANT
ABOUT A PHONE?
NO, IT'S NOT JUST THE PHONE.
THAT ONE'S PROBABLY
LOOKING AT THE INTERNET.
THAT ONE IS USING SNS WITH PICTURES.
NEXT TO THAT, MAYBE A GAME.
- GEROGERO.
- GEROGERO?
I'M A LITTLE SAD.
YOU'RE LONELY...
AH, BECAUSE THERE IS NO SOUND.
I FORGOT THE BACKGROUND MUSIC.
PUT IT ON, WITH THIS.
BUT I DON'T KNOW HOW TO DO IT...
WOH! I WAS SURPRISED.
NO ONE IS LISTENING TO IT.
- PAPA~
- HMM?
- THE SONG'S CHANGED.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
DAD, CAN YOU COME TO THE RECITAL?
I SING ALONE IN SOME PARTS.
- HEY, DAD.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
HEY, HEY.
EH?
- I'M GOING TO TAKE A PICTURE OF IT.
- LET'S TAKE A PICTURE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
HEY, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M SORRY, I'M SORRY.
YEAH~YES! HAHAHAHA...
- FUU~.
- CUTE~!
- WAS IT DONE?
- IT WAS GOOD. IT WAS CUTE~.
IT'S SO MUCH FUN!
WE WENT SHOPPING.
WE ATE A LOT OF DELICIOUS FOOD.
- THAT WAS GOOD, WASN'T IT?
- I HAD A GOOD TIME.
I'M ALREADY UP.
- WHAT? TV!
- HEY, KNOCK ON THE DOOR!
THERE'S NO DOOR.
WHAT? WHEN DID THEY START FILMING?
SO IT'S NOT TV.
IT'S TV. EH, NATIONAL TV?
I MEAN, IT'S BEING BROADCAST
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
OH, IS THAT A LETTER
FROM SOMEONE WHO SAW IT?
- YOU ARE A GOOD SINGER, AREN'T YOU?
- EH, I GOT A COMPLIMENT!
IT GOT QUITE A FEW VIEWS.
THE TRAVELER WILL WATCH TOO.
YEAH, IT'S POSSIBLE, ISN'T IT?
IF HE GETS ON SOCIAL NETWORKING SITES.
SNS? IS THAT A TV STATION?
I THINK YOU SOUND LIKE MY MOTHER SOMETIMES.
I'M SORRY, I'M AN OLD PERSON.
- I'M GOING TO TAKE A BATH.
- OH, WELL, I'M SORRY FOR INTERRUPTING.
- OOPS...
- SORRY.
"AFTER A WHILE"
OH, NO, NO, NO...
LATE ON THE FIRST DAY BACK AT WORK?
OH, MY GOD, I'M IN TROUBLE.
OH, AM I USING THE RIGHT WORD?
YES.
OH, HERE.
THIS IS NO WAY...
OUR LEFTOVERS FROM YESTERDAY'S DINNER.
I JUST PUT IT ALL TOGETHER.
NO WAY. A MAN GIVING A WOMAN A LUNCH BOX?
LOOK, YOU'RE LATE!
- NO, REIWA'S MAN IS AWESOME! I'M OFF!
- HAVE A GOOD DAY.
- AND PUT A NUMBER HERE.
- NUMBERS? - YES.
- 4... ZERO, ZERO, ZERO.
- YES
- AND ENTER.
- ENTER. OOPS!
- SEE HOW THE GRAPH HAS CHANGED?
- IT'S DONE.
I THINK IT'S CUTE THAT GIRLS
ARE WEAK WITH MACHINES.
THAT'S OLD-FASHIONED.
THAT'S PREJUDICE.
THAT'S RIGHT. MIURA-SAN. YOU SHOULD
BE CAREFUL ABOUT THAT KIND OF THING.
I'M SORRY.
WHERE IS THE
DEVELOPMENT DEPARTMENT?
DEVELOPMENT DEPARTMENT
IS ON THE THIRD FLOOR.
OH. THIS WAY PLEASE.
THE CAFE WAITRESS WHO SINGS?
- I'M A FAN.
- THE NEW ONE WAS GOOD TOO. SEE!
- OH!
- LOOK.
- THERE'S ALL THESE VIDEOS OF
CAFE CLERKS SINGING!   - VIDEO
I DIDN'T KNOW SHE WAS UPLOADING THEM.
YEAH, ONCE A WEEK.
CUTE~.
- OH, WHAT'S THAT? ISN'T THIS THE MANAGER?
- YES.
- WHO IS IT? UH... NOBI-KUN, NOBI-KUN.
- YES, YES, YES.
- SO YOU TWO GET ALONG?
- NO, NOT REALLY...
HMMM...BUT IT'S NICE, ISN'T IT?
- TODAY IS A DATE WITH PIYOMARU.
- THAT'S NICE! EH~.
- I'M HELPING OUT AT THE CAFE.
- OH~ I SEE. GOOD LUCK.
- THANKS.
- IT'S KAEDE'S BIRTHDAY TODAY.
- EH~ HAPPY BIRTHDAY.
- HAPPY BIRTHDAY.
AH~ KAEDE~!
WELCOME BACK~!
- OH, WOW~ PIYOMARU~!
- WAKA-CHAN~!
- WHOA!
- WAAA! I'M SO SURPRISED!
IT'S SO OBVIOUS.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN, THE SINGING
CAFÉ WAITRESS, SAE ISONO THIS IS
A PROMISING YOUNG THEATRICAL
TROUPE, THE FOGHORN THEATRE COMPANY.
PLEASE FEEL FREE TO UPLOAD YOUR OWN VIDEOS.
KNOCK KNOCK.
I MIGHT WANT TO STAY IN THIS WORLD FOREVER.
THAT?
MR. UEKI!
SAE-CHAN!
IT'S BEEN A WHILE!
LONG TIME NO SEE!
UEKI-SAN, YOU'RE HERE TOO!
- OVER HERE?
- OVER HERE! WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
NO, NO, NO, I'M DRINKING~.
SINCE THE ARK STOPPED SERVING SNACKS
I DON'T HAVE ANYWHERE TO GO.
WHAT DID YOU DO? COULD YOU HAVE
BEEN A SINGER?
WHAT? DID I MENTION THAT?
YOU DID SAY THAT. YOU LOVES TO SING...
I'M SINGING IN AN ARK THAT HAS
BECOME A CAFE. COME AND LISTEN.
I'M IN A RECESSION AT MY COMPANY.
BUT I'M STILL IN A SLUMP.
OI-CHAN, I'M GOING TO GO
OUT WITH ALL MY SLEEVES.
- YOU'VE GOT TO COME!
- I'M COMING!
ARE YOU AN ASPIRING SINGER?
I DON'T KNOW.
I SEE...
NOBORU IS A PLAYWRIGHT.
THAT'S GREAT.
AND HE DOESN'T EVEN MAKE A LIVING AT IT.
I'M JUST A HIRED MANAGER OF A CAFE.
- I READ YOUR SCRIPT.
- WHAT?
IT WAS VERY INTERESTING.
- REALLY?
- YEAH.
EMOTIONS ARE INTENSE?
I THINK IT'S GOING TO BE A BUZZ.
I THINK IT'S A GOOD IDEA.
THE SCENE WHERE THE HERO GENTLY
REACHES OUT TO HIS LOVER IN THE DISTANCE.
I LOVE THAT PART.
I LIKE THAT PART, TOO.
OH... NO, IT'S NOTHING.
TAKE ME TO THE SEA.
ON A SHIRT SMELLING OF CIGARETTES
GENTLY, BECAUSE I'M GOING TO LEAN IN.
AH~ HEY, HEY, HEY!
WATCH OUT, WATCH OUT! HAHAHA...
HEY, AFTER THIS, THERE'S A
MEETING OF THE THEATER TROUPE.
CAN I USE YOUR PLACE FOR A BIT?
- OH, I'LL MAKE YOU SOME DINNER.
- REALLY? YOU CAN COOK?
I CAN MAKE IT!
- THEN, PLEASE.
- YES. THEN, THIS ONE, PLEASE.
- THANK YOU.
- YES.
- MOTHER!
- I'M HOME.
WELCOME HOME.
- EVEN DINNER FOR SOMEONE ELSE.
- IF YOU'RE COMING BACK, TELL ME FIRST.
- UH-HUH... BECAUSE... I WANTED
TO TALK TO YOU IN PERSON.    - WHAT?
FROM WHAT I'VE READ, THIS
TAPIOCA CRAZE IT WON'T LAST.
UMMM... NO WAY.
- REALLY?  - REALLY
I THINK NOW IS THE TIME TO QUIT.
- I WANT TO OPEN A STORE HERE.
- HMM?
- LE CABARET DES BAS-FONDS.
- WHAT?
FRENCH STYLE.
IT WAS MY DREAM TO OPEN A BEAUTIFUL
KARAOKE SNACK BAR. IT WAS MY DREAM.
HEY! SO WHAT'S GOING
TO HAPPEN TO THE CAFE?
OH, THE CAFÉ.
IT WILL BE CLOSED.
- WHAT? WHAT ABOUT NOBORU?
- OF COURSE I KNOW HIM.
WELL, HE HAS HIS DAY JOB, TOO.
HE SAID IT'S A GOOD OPPORTUNITY.
SO, NOBORU, HE'S GOING
TO LEAVE THIS HOUSE...
WELL, THAT'S TRUE.
WELL THEN, THANKS FOR ALL
YOUR HARD WORK SO FAR! CHEERS!
CHEERS!
ARE YOU CELEBRATING THE COMPLETION
OF THE SCRIPT? I KNOW, RIGHT?
- OH, NO!
- OH, NO! DON'T TELL ME WHAT'S IN THERE.
SPOILERS, YOU MEAN? NO!
THUS, I'M CURIOUS.
I HAVEN'T FINISHED WRITING.
WE'RE BREAKING UP.
WHAT? YOU'RE DISSOLVING THE TROUPE?
WE'RE GOING TO DO IT UNTIL THE NEXT SHOW.
BUT WE CAN'T AFFORD IT ANYMORE.
- I'M TOO OLD FOR THIS.
- BUT WE WORKED PRETTY HARD, DIDN'T WE?
WE ARE THE BEST IN OUR GENERATION.
WHY NOT? NOBORU-KUN, AREN'T YOU
GOING TO STOP WORKING AT THE CAFÉ?
I THOUGHT YOU WERE GOING TO
CONCENTRATE ON YOUR ACTING.
- NO... BECAUSE IT DOESN'T SELL.
- BUT...
SAE...
YOU ARE FREE TO DO IT, YOU ARE FREE
NOT TO DO IT. THAT'S THE ERA, RIGHT?
IT'S OUR RESPONSIBILITY.
OKAY, YOU CAN ALL DRINK
AS MUCH AS YOU WANT.
- IT'S ON ME!
- YESSSS~!
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I THINK I'LL GET SOME KNOB.
THANK YOU. HEY, DID
YOU EAT THE RICE BALL?
I DID.
ARE YOU EATING?
JUST SOMETHING SIMPLE, RIGHT?
I WILL MISS YOU.
IT CAN'T BE HELPED.
I'LL SEE YOU ALL AGAIN.
I WANTED YOU TO TELL ME.
I WANTED YOU TO TELL ME ABOUT
QUITTING THE TROUPE AND MOVING OUT.
I HAVE TO REFRAIN FROM
TALKING ABOUT DARK THINGS.
I'M JUST A ROOMMATE.
BORING, SHARING A HOUSE.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR HELP.
JUBILEE? DID SHE REMARRY?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
THE CONTRACT EXPIRED, NORMALLY.
OUT OF CONTRACT?
BUT IT'S NOT EXPIRATION, IT'S TERMINATION.
DISPATCH TERMINATION.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR HELP.
I'M UNEMPLOYED WITH CHILDREN.
IT'S ITTY BITTY TO BE EXCITED, ISN'T IT?
THE WAY YOU ARE TALKING IS OLD AND WEEDY.
IS THIS A BAD WORD?
- WAKA-SA~.
- HMM?
DO YOU LIKE THIS PERIOD?
- HMMM... I HAVEN'T THOUGHT ABOUT IT.
- WHY?
- MAYBE I DIDN'T SEE IT.
- WHAT?
IN THIS PERIOD
I ONLY SAW THE GOOD PARTS.
WHAT? ARE YOU SAYING THAT
THE OLD DAYS WERE BETTER?
THAT'S NOT WHAT I MEANT.
BUT IF WE HAD STAYED IN OUR ORIGINAL WORLD
I WONDER WHAT HE WOULD HAVE DONE.
I WANTED YOU TO READ IT FIRST.
I'M OFF TO STOCK UP TOMORROW.
WHAT'S UP?
YOU'RE TRYING TO WRITE SOMETHING
INTERESTING LIKE THIS. YOU CAN'T STOP!
I'M NOT GOING TO
STOP WRITING AT ALL.
EVEN IF I GET A JOB, I'LL
CONTINUE TO WRITE IN DETAIL...
YOU WANT TO GET A JOB?
WHILE WRITING?
I'M NOT AIMING FOR IT IN THE FIRST PLACE.
- I JUST LIKE IT...
- LIAR.
I JUST WANT TO DO IT AT MY OWN PACE.
I HAVE MORE IMPORTANT THINGS TO DO
THAN SELL OR MAKE MONEY OR WHATEVER.
YOU WANT TO BE RICH AND HAVE A NICE CAR.
OR WANT TO WORK HARD AND GET AHEAD.
YOU WANT THAT.
YOU ARE TOO HUMBLE NOW.
MAKING FUN OF UPWARD MOBILITY
IN A WORLD OF CONVENIENCE.
IT'S JUST A SMALL GROUP.
HEY, WAIT!
I KNOW, RIGHT?
YOU'RE SUCH A GOOD SINGER.
YOU GAVE UP BEING A SINGER, DIDN'T YOU?
IT'S THE SAME THING.
NO, IT'S NOT.
IN THE REAL WORLD....
IN THE REAL WORLD... I
WANTED TO BE A SINGER.
BUT... INSTEAD OF REALLY TRYING...
I MADE EXCUSES AND RAN AWAY.
YOU RAN AWAY, DIDN'T YOU?
JUST BE YOUR TRUE SELF.
THERE IS, ISN'T THERE? THERE
IS A REAL WORLD, ISN'T THERE?
THEN...
I MIGHT NOT BE ABLE TO SEE YOU.
HUH? WHAT?
ENOUGH.
FOR EXAMPLE, EVEN IF I AM WRONG...
SAE!
I FOUND YOU. IT'S A MIRACLE.
DID YOU LOOK FOR ME?
IT'S LIKE AN OLD DRAMA.
- OH, IT'S DAZZLING.
- OH, SORRY, SORRY.
I'LL DO IT.
THANKS.
ARE YOU LEAVING?
WHAT?
TO THE REAL WORLD.
I'M THINKING OF DOING A LITTLE MORE.
- YEAH.
I'M GOING TO CONTINUE WITH THE TROUPE.
I WANT TO DO MY BEST.
BUT... I'M SUPER NERVOUS.
WHAT?
I'M THINKING THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
YOU'VE EVER TALKED TO ME ABOUT IT.
OH... I DON'T KNOW.
YEAH.
WHAT ABOUT YOU? WHAT
ARE YOU GOING TO DO?
I'M GOING TO GO CHANGE MY CLOTHES.
I KNEW IT WAS TRUE.
EVEN IF TIMES CHANGE, EVEN IF THE
WORLD CHANGES, NOTHING CHANGES.
I HAVE TO CHANGE.
- SAE-CHAN!
- YOU'RE SO CUTE!
TODAY'S THE FAREWELL PARTY OF CAFE ARK.
IT'S ALSO A ONE-NIGHT REVIVAL PARTY.
YES!
NO CHARGE WILL BE MADE. DRINKING AND
SINGING, CELEBRATE THE ARK'S NEW BEGINNING!
YES~YES!
CUTE!
BEAUTIFUL!
TODAY, TOO, SOMEONE IS INTOXICATED BY SONG
SONGS CONNECT PEOPLE TO PEOPLE,
SONGS ARE FOR EVERYONE
GIVE ME A BEER, PLEASE!
- THANKS FOR YOUR HARD WORK~.
- THANKS.   - YOU WERE CUTE!
- HERE YOU GO.
- THANK YOU.
- OH, HEY, I GOT A NEW PLACE TO WORK~.
- WE'RE GLAD~.
I THINK I CAN MANAGE THE DAY-CARE
CENTER TOO. I'M SORRY FOR WORRYING YOU.
- NO PROBLEM.
- THEN WE HAVE TO DRINK.
- WE HAVE TO DRINK.
- CONGRATULATIONS.
SAE!
LEAVE IT TO ME!
- HMM?
- I'LL TAKE CARE OF IT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THOSE GUYS.
THAT'S GOOD. ISN'T
THAT THE POWER OF SONG?
SAE.
SING IT. THE LAST SONG.
YEAH...
- WAIT A MINUTE.
- YEAH.
I JUST WANTED TO
HEAR YOUR SONG AGAIN.
I HAD A FEELING YOU WOULD COME.
WERE YOU HAPPY
IN A DIFFERENT TIME?
WHEN I GO BACK....
IF I GO BACK, EVERYTHING WILL BE GONE?
WHAT'S INSIDE YOU
WON'T DISAPPEAR.
EH... LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
AT THE END OF THE NIGHT,
FROM SAE ISONO WHO'S WELL KNOWN AS
A SINGING CAFE WAITRESS. SAE ISONO-SAN
I WOULD LIKE TO SEND A SONG TO ALL OF YOU.
- SAE-CHAN!  - SAE-SAN!
- ISONO-KUN!
SAE-CHAN!
HEY, LADY!
NOW I WANT TO BRING A SONG
TO YOU.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
UNTIL WE MEET AGAIN.
I WANT TO DELIVER A SONG
TO ALL OF YOU.
- GO... SEE...
- AH...
- ARE YOU OKAY?
I'M GOING TO GO.
I'M GOING TO GO TO THE
SOMEDAY, WITH THE REAL
ME, WITH THE REAL YOU.
SOMEDAY,
REMEMBER... UNTIL WE MEET AGAIN.
ARE YOU OKAY?
I LOVE YOU~!
- SAE-CHAN, BEER!
- BEER? WHICH ONE?
HERE YOU GO.
BACK TO THE ORIGINAL TIME
EVERYTHING IS BACK TO NORMAL THOUGH.
A LITTLE BIT I CHANGED.
WORKING HARD.
I KEEP AUDITIONING
MY MOTHER HERE ALSO HAD A CHANGE. SHE STARTED
SAYING SHE WAS GOING TO STUDY IN FRANCE
MOM, I'M AMAZED YOU
DECIDED TO STUDY ABROAD.
IF YOU REALLY WANT TO DO SOMETHING,
DON'T YOU? I'M SURE YOU'LL START SOMEDAY.
I THINK SO.
THE REMAINING FIRE THAT WAS SMOLDERING IN
YOUR HEART, I THINK IT'S STARTING TO BURN.
I HOPE IT WASN'T TOO
HARD FOR DAD.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- WHAT?
ACH... YOUR FATHER, YOU KNOW.
HE WAS ON FIRE.
HE ALREADY LIVED OUT HIS LIFE THE WAY HE
WANT TO, AND BURNED UP COMPLETELY. PHEW.
DONE.
SO... WAS IT?
YES, IT WAS.
SO, YOU KNOW, YOU DON'T
HAVE TO PUT OUT YOUR FIRE.
YEAH, I KNOW.
HELLO
HELLO.
ENGLISH SUBTITLES
FROM CHRIZ GUTIERREZ