(チャイム)
Oh no... Why are you always
talking to me as if I'm your friend?
- Teacher, because I feel close to you.
- I see. Well, that's no wonder...
- You idiot! Use honorifics!
- I want my phone back.
How many times do I have to tell you?
- Don't look at Twitter during class.
- I'm not looking.
- So you're on INSTAGRAM?
- I don't do INSTAGRAM either.
- What were you looking?
- A drama.
That's it.
Drama? Drama in class?
- Yes, but I can finish it in five minutes.
- Five minutes?
So you were just in time...
You idiot! You're out, you're out!
There's no way you can finish
watching a drama in 5 minutes.
Teacher, a 1 hour drama
now can be in double speed.
It takes about 10 minutes. I know
some kids watch it in about 10 minutes.
Wait a minute.
Watch it at normal speed.
- The person who made this is going to cry.
- But I was watching earlier.
The drama is in normal speed,
and it takes 5 minutes.
How is that possible... is that possible?
- Do you want to see it?
- Really?
A drama in five minutes...
- There you go.
- What... which one... hmm?
SURPRISING ENDING AFTER FIVE MINUTES
CURSED RING
Welcome.
This is good.
French vintage parts from 18th Century.
That necklace is very well preserved.
A rare and valuable piece.
And that is?
Oh... that?
Lovely
100 million?
Yes.
- I'll take it.
- Eh?
I've never seen a ring
that draws me in like this.
- I'll take it.
- But...
A young woman like me...
You think I'm out of it?
Oh, no...
This is my husband.
He's smart, tall, and
in addition, he is a wealthy man.
If I say I want something,
he'll buy me anything I want.
So you don't have to worry about money.
No, it's not about money
I can't sell this ring to anyone.
If it's in the store, that
means it's a product, right?
Yes, it's a product but
I don't intend to sell it.
Then why there is a price on it?
- There is a reason for that...
- Anyway, sell it.
I like this ring.
Oh, actually, this is
already a sold-out item...
- That's not what you're saying!
- No, that's not what I'm saying...
Okay, I'll give you more.
If it's higher than this,
would you sell it to me?
No, I can't. I can't sell it to
you under any circumstances.
If you don't intend to sell it,
why do you have it here for sale?
I'm asking you!
- It's...
- I heard it's sold out or something.
You even told a blatant lie.
I'm not happy about it!
Okay, let's talk about it.
That ring is a cursed ring.
Cursed... you say?
Yes... So far, several people have been
the owner of that ring.
But those people
died an unnatural death in every case.
I was told that there
was a curse on that ring.
It became a myth.
And it just flowed on and
on, and now here it is...
Only that thing.
How can they charge such a high price?
It's a measure to prevent it from selling.
As long as it is on display,
that ring is not mine.
The curse does not fall on me.
The previous owner of
the store didn't want to sell it
and due to an unfortunate accident,
he passed away.
That's ridiculous!
I don't think that's possible!
- Ma'am...
- YOU must give me this ring.
I'm sure you're just being lax, aren't you?
- No, I'm not.
- There is no such thing as a curse!
You've got to be kidding me!
If you really don't want to sell this ring,
I'll just buy the whole store.
And get rid of you!
I understand,
but no matter what happens,
I will not take responsibility, okay?
OK.
Okay, I'll wrap it up for you.
- I have a favor to ask.
- Yes?
I'd like to have that ring sized.
If it's your hand
I think it's about right.
No, it's not, about 180cm tall.
I want it to be big enough to fit on
a man's finger. I want you to fix it.
This is my husband.
Because it's
a cursed ring, isn't it?
Yes, ma'am.
I will fix it right away.
If you no longer need
the ring, please contact us.
We will buy it back from you.
I don't want it to become your property.
Thank you.
- Teacher! Teacher!
- Oh! Oh...!
- Are you all right that you froze up?
- No, I'm horrified
I don't know anything but
her husband is pathetic.
Your ring is also a "cursed ring".
Stop it. It's not. You know,
This is from... I'm married you know...
You little...
What? Ah... ah!
THE RING GOT TIGHT
AFTER 5 YEARS OF MARRIAGE
- Teacher, do you want to see the next one?
- Yes, I do.
- Next one's 5 minutes too?
- Yes, about that much.
Let's see.
This one looks scary, too. Yeah?
A murderer lives in the house next to me.
A serial killer has just been
being taken away by the police.
When I was 4 years old
I saw him being arrested.
I saw him on the news.
I'll kill you!
He's out... of prison.
THE KILLER WHO LIVES NEXT DOOR
2010 MURDER CASE
You should take a bath.
- I'm telling you!
- So annoying!
Hey!
Have you talked to the guy
who moved in next door?
I at least said hello.
Hurry and go bath.
I forgot about the old days
I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
I'll kill you!
I can't forget those crazy eyes.
I'm going to kill you
I'll kill you... I'll kill you!
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
Be careful.
Ouch.
He's so hurt...
Hey, man...
Yes.
Can I borrow your shoulder?
We're going in the same direction.
- Sorry.
- No...
You know me?
- What?
- Just now
you said, "We're going in
the same direction.", right?
Oh...
You're the kid next door, right? I can
remember other people's faces easily.
What's wrong?
When you got caught,
I still remember.
I was four years old.
I saw it on the news.
I was really scared of your face.
I couldn't move...
You were watching...
You may have committed a crime, but
you have atoned for your sins, haven't you?
It's funny for me to say this, but
you can do it.
No matter what people around you say,
you saved that boy,
I know you would've done it.
I think you can do it.
I thought the world
would never accept me.
I thought people would
never accept me anymore.
I just gave up.
I was just like, "This is the end".
But if there is someone who thinks
like that, I'm not going to give up now.
I may still be able to do my best.
Thanks.
- Ugh...
- Are you okay?
No, I'm not... sorry.
1 MONTH LATER
People can start over again and again,
as long as they have life.
- Hold this.
- I'll help you with that.
- I think it's our mission as doctors.
- Dr. Zaitsu.
I am... I think...
You know
I saw it on TV yesterday.
You were an actor, wasn't you?
Dr. Zaitsu...
Thanks to you
I feel much better.
I saw it when I was little,
it was a scene from a detective drama.
I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
That's what you were
saying here, wasn't it?
I've been clinging to those memories.
That was the biggest role
I've ever played in my life.
But recently I haven't had any work at all.
I'm already over 50 years old
and I have no talent.
I've been thinking about
giving up acting for months.
But you told me that I could do it.
You said, "You know, I still remember it."
I was so scared I couldn't move.",
you said.
I was able to stay it in my memory.
If you feel that way, I can try again.
Even from now,
I thought, "I can do my best".
No, I thought, "I will do my very best."
You are the one who gave me
the courage to try again. Thank you.
Don't mind it.
Actually, I'm about to
go to an audition today.
I'll let you know first about it.
I thought it was a horror story,
that was a good story.
- Did you see how it unfolded?
- No, not at all!
Actually, he's an actor, right?
I was in the drama club in high school.
But I never got to be on stage.
- I see...
- Yeah.
5 DAYS AFTER I ENTERED, I LEFT THE CLUB
Because, there's only three of us.
We're only three in THE LION KING,
We don't have enough animals, really.
Yeah... I was worried a lot.
If only that theater group
would've pulled their shit together,
I'd be in Tom Hanks' class right now.
I think I learned how to act.
Whoa, let's see what's next! Hey!
- I have something to do now.
- What?
- That's it for today!
- Hey, come on! It's only five minutes.
- Goodbye!
- Five minutes? You...
Going to go to Gotanda from Oosaki...
I can't help it.
THE FOLLOWING EPISODE OF
SURPRISING ENDING AFTER FIVE MINUTES
RAWS PROVIDED BY HIKARI RIDERS
ENGLISH TRANSLATION FROM DEEPL
ENGLISH SUBTITLES FROM CHRIZ KAYRIKO
THIS DRAMA IS FICTION
If you want to watch this
drama again, please go to TVer.