What is it, teacher?
- I bought this.
- Oh! You changed your cellphone?
Then with this teacher,
- you can watch that drama!
- But I don't know how to do it.
- Please help me.
- You're kidding, right?
- Is that the reason why you called me?
- Yes, help me.
You know in class earlier, I know
you're in YouTube or Twitter, right?
- I'm not on Twitter.
- Then you're on Instagram?
- Well... on an insta-live.
- That's it, live streaming.
Hey, you,
don't stream during class!
You should do that when you get home!
- Okay, I'm going home.
- No, that's not what I meant!
Hey! Look, look...
Wait Mother Teresa,
bring me to life too.
- Come on! Come on!
- Alright.
Whoa, great!
Where did you press it?
SUPRISE ENDING AFTER FIVE MINUTES
#SURPRISEGIFT
Hey! You're slacking off.
I'm sorry.
How did this happen?
Chiho, let's get married!
- What?
- Since the other day,
They asked me if I'd be interested
in a full-time position in the office.
I thought I should take it.
From now on,
I'm going to get a proper job.
- What about your band?
- What?
- That's...
Well... we didn't get any audition at all.
I'm not very excited about it.
I think it's time to face reality.
And when I think about Chiho,
I can't work part-time all the time.
I can't continue like that forever.
- That's why...
- That's not
what I want!
I'm sure you can become
a world-famous musician.
- I really believe it.
- What..
- I will chase a dream like that?
- Are you going to run away?
What I want is...
I want Chiho to be happy.
That's what I really want!
So I got a job properly.
Then why are you giving up?
Are you wearing a suit while on the train
so your dreams will come true?
I can wait forever for your dreams though!
Chiho...
This thing kind of thing...
is not what I want.
There are things more
important than dreams.
Why don't you understand my feelings?
Don't tell me...
She doesn't want to marry me?
I'm not worthy of her anymore?
Maybe she's moving out of the house now...
What are you mumbling about?
- Senpai, please let me leave early!
- What?
- I'm really sorry!
- Hey!
Chiho...
Chiho!
Chiho! Chiho, are you there?
- Chiho!
- Don't come!
Why are you saying that?
How's your part-time job? What's going on?
I just want to see you!
Let me be alone!
That's...
Don't tell me... it is for me?
Yeah, If you're going to work
for a company, you will need it.
I'm sorry about yesterday.
I got out of control because of
the suddenness of conversation.
But I thought you were
serious about our future.
I realized that.
Oh, I was going to surprise you.
Ouch.
On how you behaved yesterday,
I know you were so serious about my dream.
And yet... I doubted your love.
I'm such a stupid man!
Junpei...
You are the best woman in the world.
I will cherish you for the rest of my life!
Alright.
That woman...
No way! You've got a boyfriend.
- I still want to have fun.
- Are you?
Well, if I didn't found anyone else,
I'd be happy to marry you.
Oh, really?
But you can still play with me.
Chiho! Chiho, are you there?
- Chiho!
- Don't come!
Why are you saying that?
I just want to see you!
Let me be alone!
Thank you.
Wow... so beautiful!
How can I get back my suit?
This man on the balcony,
did he got home safe?
He wears only briefs,
even if you get off the balcony safely.
How the hell are he supposed to move?
But you teacher is like Junpei too.
Be careful not to be fooled.
Hey, don't compare others on your own.
Hey, I want to see
a picture of your wife.
- Why?
- Let me see if she's like Chiho.
She's not like Chiho!
A woman knows a lot more than men.
- No, no need for it.
- It's in there, isn't it? Let me see.
Hey, stop it! Risa, stop!
Stop it already!
CLOSED ROOM GAME
What is this place?
Hey! Somebody! Is anyone there?
Good morning.
You just got have a good rest until now.
Is this a prank or something?
As expected from a leading popular actor,
that's the kind of idea they think.
But you are wrong.
Then what's your point?
You've got me trapped in a
place like this, is it for money?
I do not want money.
I just want to play a game with you.
Game?
Yes. You're betting your life on it.
The rules are simple, all you
have to do is answer my questions.
But don't lie.
If you don't answer
honestly, you will be killed.
What is this nonsense...
What is this joke now!
Okay, the first question:
Have you ever done a thing,
just for your personal desires?
There isn't.
Really?
No matter how long it takes,
the night will always end!
Good.
I've never brought anyone down.
The only reason I'm in this
position is because of me!
That's a lie.
I told you, right?
If you give a false
answer, I'm going to kill you.
About 20 years ago,
I went to a fellow actor's place.
I got an offer to play the leading
role in a stage play and I want to do it.
But he took it from me.
So I did a little work on the set.
That guy just happened
to be in an accident,
and I got the lead role.
The night will definitely come!
If you call that entrapment.
I think you've caved in.
That's correct.
You, are you that guy from back then?
You're trying to get revenge!
Okay, next question, 12 years ago,
your manager caused the accident?
Please answer me.
How many times do I
have to say the same thing?
Enough!
You want me to say
that the accident was my fault?
He was a psychiatrist.
He told me it was my fault.
I yelled at him and stuff like that,
so he has no choice.
But you know what? I'm
under a lot more stress than him!
In an industry where merit
is the only thing that counts,
I have to keep being a popular actor!
And that's the manager's job!
After all, he's a sick man at heart.
He drinks tranquilizers in
large doses even before driving.
And that's how he got into an accident.
You're satisfied with this much talking?
That's good. Okay, next.
That's enough!
Who the hell are you?
Do you love your wife and daughter?
What the hell, suddenly you ask...
I'll draw it.
Oh, yeah! You're good at it!
- Here you go...
- Wow! Delicious looking fruits are here.
- Thank you.
- Yes!
Of course.
Of course, in a marriage,
I love my wife and my daughter.
Now then, how many
children do you have?
What's wrong?
Are you... Yosuke?
More than 20 years ago, before I was
married and before my daughter was born,
I loved a woman once other than my wife.
He was born to her.
That's Yosuke.
But if an illegitimate child is discovered,
my acting career will be over.
In exchange of continuing
to pay child support,
I asked them to keep the truth quiet.
If Yosuke heard about that,
it doesn't matter if he
have a grudge against me.
But Yosuke,
I want you to understand one thing.
I didn't abandon you and your mother!
I loved your mother.
I'm not lying!
I don't care about any of that!
Quickly tell me the answer to my question.
How many children do you have?
I have two children.
That's incorrect.
What do you mean?
I have no one but only him and my daughter.
That's all. I didn't lie!
The correct answer is
"I have only one child."
So Yosuke is not my child?
To cheat me out of my money...
No. He is indeed your child.
What?
Do you understand?
The one who is not your
child is your daughter.
What nonsense...
That can't be true!
You can understand, can't you?
"I once had feelings for a
woman who was not my wife."
Only if it's you only.
Don't tell me...
You can understand, can't you?
"I once had feelings for a
woman who was not my wife."
Only if it's you only.
No way.
- I'll draw you a bear too.
- Yes.
I'll draw a lot here too.
You are the one?
What does this mean?
It's just like you.
I too loved a man who was not my husband
and gave birth to my daughter.
You understand, don't you?
Hey, honey?
Goodbye.
Ma'am, you're being very presentive.
She've prepared so much.
That amazing room,
did she build it all by yourself?
- I don't think so.
- It's a fad - DIY.
- I'm going home.
- What?
- Goodbye.
- No, hey...
Don't talk like the scary wife.
- Let's watch one more...
- What?
I just bought it but
it's already broken!
Oh, it's so black!
- Where's your charger?
- What?
I didn't bring one.
If you have a spare, lend it to me.
I can't help it.
What is these?
That's a lot of choices!
Wow, that's great!
Unseasonal Santa Claus,
thanks for the surprise gift.
This will bring me back to life too.
- Well, I'm going home.
- Wait for this.
NEXT EPISODE OF SURPRISE
ENDING AFTER FIVE MINUTES
RAWS & JP SUBS PROVIDER
@hikaririders.
TRANSLATION TOOL
DeepL
ENGLISH SUBTITLES
Chriz Kayriko (@chrizkayriko)
THIS DRAMA IS FICTION.
If you want to watch this
drama again, please go to TVer.