- Teacher, what do you need?
- Oh!
Sit down! Sit down!
You know, the other day...
What was it, five minutes is critical?
No, no.
"Five minutes later, it ends unexpectedly."
That's it. I just want to see it again.
Is that why you called me here?
Why don't you just watch it yourself?
Well then, let me ask you something.
How can I see it with this?
A mobile phone? No way.
Yes, it is.
- Please, Generation Z.
- Hey, don't call me that!
Please! Please!
As expected of Generation Z.
You work fast.
Generation Z? Stop it!
SURPRISE ENDING AFTER 5 MINUTES
LIAR
- Are you nervous?
- Yes... but being a motorcycle policemen
is what I've been longing for it
since I was little. I'm glad!
You'll be fine, as long
as you take it easy.
When it's over, let's have a debut party.
Yes.
I'll be patrolling there.
Call me if you find anything.
Yes.
OK!
Here it comes!
Stop right there! Please stop!
What?
Don't be scared, don't be scared...
Don't drive like that.
It's dangerous!
- I wasn't driving that fast.
- I saw you pass by my side.
You were going over the
legal speed limit of 30km/hr!
Please come outside.
- Please present your driver's license.
- I don't have one.
- What?
- I got a speeding ticket a year ago.
You mean you're
driving without a license?
Yes.
What a bad driver!
This car belongs to you, doesn't it?
Of course not!
I can't drive this car!
- Whose car is it?
- I don't know. I stole it.
Stolen?
Speeding, driving without a license,
and theft! I'll take that as a "yes".
Yes he is a bad guy...
and he's totally unfazed.
What the hell is this guy?
Can I check the vehicle
registration certificate?
Then we can see who this car belongs to.
Vehicle registration? Yes, just now,
I may have seen it when
I put my handgun away.
A handgun?
Is there a handgun in there?
I'm not going to say it again!
Oh no... This is too bad...
This guy's not just a bad man!
I can't believe it's such a
serious case for the first time.
What am I going to do?
- Oh, I remember now.
- Yes.
The owner of this car is a woman.
I killed her with that gun.
You... killed her?
Yes, that's right.
He killed a woman, and he's just fine!
This is what you call a psychopath.
I can't handle this!
I'll be back in a minute.
Senpai! Excuse me.
Please back me up.
- What's wrong?
- There's a...
Hey, hey, hey!
Where are you going?
I'm in a hurry.
I'm on my way to dump the
dead body in the mountains.
Is there a dead body on board?
Yeah, it's in the trunk right now.
Yeah, there's a dead body there...
Let's take a look, shall we?
Look.
- Hey.
- Senpai!
- What happened?
- That... that guy.
I stopped him from speeding.
He said he didn't have his driver's
license and that he stole the car.
The gun was near the dashboard.
In the trunk, I'm told
there's a dead body.
Okay. Calm down!
- I'll handle it here. You call for backup.
- Yes.
Take care. Be careful.
- You never know what he might do.
- Alright.
Excuse me! Let us ask you again.
You mean you don't
have a driver's license?
- I do have a driver's license.
- What?
- Doesn't sound fake to me.
- Of course.
This car is not stolen?
Of course, it's mine!
I also have a vehicle
registration certificate.
I don't understand...
The dashboard, may I see it?
Go ahead.
No handgun...
Hadgun? There is no way there is!
Let's see the trunk, too.
That's not what he said.
What did he report to you?
That you were driving
a stolen car with no
license and you are in
possession of a handgun.
- He said you're carrying a dead body.
- Dead body? There's no such thing!
That's right...
That cop is a liar.
Maybe there are other lies?
I was speeding.
I'm sorry.
Huh~ I didn't expect this ending.
Teacher, you're an ex-drama club member.
When a thing happened,
Why don't you tell
a brilliant lie like that?
I can't act like that.
- You can do it.
- I can't do it.
- Then, let's go.
- What?
Oh, wheeen, yes!
- Sir, license out!
- What? I'm sorry!
I wasn't even going 10 kilometers.
Please wait a minute.
I'm sorry. This is a point card.
This is my number card.
This is the fourth one...
Oh, it's the fifth one.
I'm sorry. Here it is.
No, this is an insurance card!
SURPRISE MISTAKE ON THE FIFTH CARD
What's that, teacher?
Generation Z doesn't understand the
carotid docking then dying.
Booooo!
THE GRIM REAPER
Your disease is stomach cancer.
Stomach cancer?
Yes, of the skilful type.
This is the area that has been
eroded by the cancer cells.
The cancer has metastasized deep
into the lungs. It is now in stage 4.
At this point,
surgery will be difficult.
Wait a minute. That means
does that mean there's
nothing we can do?
Yes.
Okay, so how much more do I have?
If you do not receive
life-prolonging treatment,
I think it is unlikely that you will be
able to see the cherry blossoms next year.
I would like to explain about the
life-prolonging treatment.
The main treatment is
chemotherapy or radiation therapy.
Chemotherapy is
so-called anticancer drug therapy.
It's a drug that
kills cancer cells but
it also attacks normal cells.
You haven't eaten at all.
What's wrong? Eat properly.
I still have some of
yesterday's sake left over.
You've been drinking too
much lately, haven't you?
When you become a member of society,
you have a lot of social life.
Oh, by the way, what
did your physician said?
Oh, he said I have a little
metabolic syndrome.
What?
Oh, man, they're going
to say that to me, too.
At your age?
Eat your vegetables, vegetables.
I said I can't eat.
You should eat tomatoes, too.
Father?
If no life-prolonging treatment is given,
I think the possibility of seeing
cherry blossoms next year is low.
I think it is low.
DIR. WATANABE
I wonder what kind of family
Shoichi is going to build.
I'm going to die without
seeing my grandchildren.
I'm sorry, Masami,
I said we'd travel to many places.
Why? Why me?
MASAMI TAKAMURA
I have to tell the truth.
We'll figure it out together.
Daddy, where are you?
At the park.
You're absent today?
I got a call from your manager, though.
Well...
Hey, what's going on?
Something strange happened
since yesterday, didn't it?
Masami...
- There was a call from the hospital.
- Eh?
There was a mistake,
they want me to come over right now.
I am very sorry.
The one I showed you yesterday
is from another patient.
What?
To a man with the
same last name,
It looks like the x-ray
technician made a mistake.
Yours is here.
You have a little bit of
gastroptosis but no worries.
So I don't have cancer?
Yes, I am sorry.
- What about next year's cherry blossoms?
- You can see it without problem.
Ahh, really!
Thank God! I'm so glad!
I mean, It's bad, doctor!
Do you have any idea
I've been through so much!
I am very sorry.
Now doctor, you kind
of looks like a Buddha.
You look like a different
person yesterday.
How did I look like yesterday?
What a thing to say,
A grim repear?
Yes, yes.
Yay!
I can still live!
- Daddy!
- Oh, what's wrong?
What "what's wrong"?
You're acting strange.
At the check-up,
I thought they might have found something.
- Nothing.
- Really?
Yeah, I'm in perfect health.
Oh, don't make me worry about you.
See, I told you he's fine.
Hey, let's have lunch together.
I want to plan a trip.
Trip? What's going on all of a sudden?
Didn't I said we'd travel to places?
It's been a long time since
we've been together as a family.
Great!
Let me know when you decide
on a restaurant. I'll join you later.
How is Shoichi?
Yeah, he had a medical checkup.
I think there was a mistake.
I just met him here by chance.
The x-ray technician made a mistake
to a one with the same last name.
Daddy!
No, you can't go!
Grim repear?
There's the grim geaper!
Grim reaper?
A death sentence is waiting for you!
Shoichi!
Oh no, from the bottom
to the further bottom.
He never had such a hard time as a parent.
I'd rather be told to myself.
Ohh, I didn't like the ending.
Okay, I've made up my mind.
I'm not going to get a
check-up this year. It's scary.
- No, you should go.
- I don't want to.
A reaper with a doctor's face,
I'm scared.
I wonder what a real
grim reaper looks like.
The face of a grim reaper? Hmmm...
The face of a grim reaper in
5, 4, 3, 2, 1,
Cue!
It's duplicitous!
Good evening, I am a grim reaper.
SURPRISE HIGH TONE OF
VOICE AFTER FIVE SECONDS
Let's get it back.
Oh, Rina, your college,
they're talking to your
recommendation about badminton.
Really?
What do you think?
THE FOLLOWING EPISODE OF
SURPRISE ENDING AFTER FIVE MINUTES
RAWS & JP SUBS PROVIDER
@hikaririders.
TRANSLATION TOOL
DeepL
ENGLISH SUBTITLE
Chriz Kayriko (CHRIZsubs)
THIS DRAMA IS FICTION
If you want to watch this
drama again, please go to TVer.
ENGLISH SUBTITLES FROM CHRIZ KAYRIKO