Sensei, did you fix your phone?
Then we can't watch that drama anymore.
That's right. I'm so shocked that
my ninja glasses almost slipped off.
Ah... but can't we watch
it on the school tablet?
Huh? Look, that one...
On this board-like thing?
Sensei, you haven't been using that, right?
No, I use it to calculate things.
- Just as a calculator?
- What else can you use it for?
Isn't it mainly used for
school notifications now?
No wonder... I thought I was
missing out on a lot of things.
Turns out I didn't know about them.
Sensei, are you okay?
Well, that's not important.
But can we really watch it?
On this board-like thing?
Yeah, of course!
Wow, you know a lot of stuff.
Here!
SURPRISING ENDING AFTER 5 MINUTES
"It's said you can hear a
sound when you fall in love."
Today, the second semester begins.
Some of you might still be
in summer vacation mode...
"I wonder when I became so
obsessed with romance novels...
Among them, the story of 'Haru and Aki'...
Is special."
"I heard it. The sound of a heartbeat..."
"This must be love."
THE FAILED CUPID
Shio-chan! Shio-chan, sorry.
Could I borrow your notes?
Ah, of course... here.
Thanks.
Wow! Your handwriting is so neat.
Really?
Yeah. It's like the
teacher's handwriting.
- Not at all.
- No, no, no.
There you go again.
By the way, isn't the name "Loves books
more than meals" kind of old-fashioned?
But...
Eh, Haruma, you're
not coming on Saturday?
Another movie again.
I told you that I love
movies more than meals.
Haruma! You forgot your meals again.
I brought it from your aunt.
Ah, sorry.
The usual thanks is fine, you movie idiot.
I'm not an idiot.
- It'd be easier if you admit it.
- No, Sanae, you...
- What?
- Using just her name...
Ah, being childhood friends is nice.
Ahh, can't I create one too, a
handsome childhood friend, starting now?
- Anyway, take a look at this.
- Another movie?
This is a masterpiece.
Jim Jarmusch's Coffee and Cigarettes.
You'll definitely get it too, you guys.
The charm of an omnibus film.
A MASTERPIECE OF ROMANCE OMNIBUS...
You're not going?
"After all... this is love."
"I love you.
If we could become a
couple like Haru and Aki,
I'd be happy."
Ah, um!
What?
Omnibus.
Omnibus?
I heard you talking the other day.
About omnibus films.
This book is like that too.
So, um...
I thought maybe
Haruma would like it too.
Ah, you're lending me the book?
Yes!
And if it's okay, I'd love
to hear your thoughts.
Ah, thoughts...
I might not be good at saying them, but...
Got it. Thanks.
"But two weeks passed,
and neither the book nor
the thoughts came back."
Ah...
Sorry. Could you wait a
little longer for the book?
Ah, sure. Of course!
It's totally fine.
Hey, did you hear?
Haruma and Sanae are dating!
Isn't a childhood love so wonderful?
"In reality, love isn't like a novel."
So, how did you get
confessed to, Yuki-san?
So, the one who confessed first was her.
Yeah, yeah... and then?
Sanae said, “I could go out
with you,” with a superior tone.
Oh? Bragging, are we, you idiot!
- Ah, here.
- I'll return it.
Ah, Shio-chan! Shio-chan!
Emi... Sanae too...
- Ah, we're about to go...
- Congrats. Huh?
The confession? It went well.
I overheard it
by chance in the classroom.
Sanae said, "I could go out with you."
Eh, he said that?
- No, that's not it.
- Huh? But...
It was from an omnibus
romance novel, I think?
Haruma lent me a book.
On the last page of it...
The last page?
Yes. There...
"I like you. If we could become
a couple like Haru and Aki, I'd be happy."
What, a love confession?
Ahh, that's just too wonderful.
"Ah, thoughts...
I might not be good
at saying them, but...
Sorry. Could you read this book
and tell me your thoughts?"
"I love you.
If we could become a couple
like Haru and Aki, I'd be happy."
Both the confession and
the reason were from me.
Ah, we're going to see the
basketball team's match...
Shio-chan, wanna come with us?
Ah... I'm good for today. Thanks.
Oh, really? Well, tomorrow then.
- Bye-bye.
There's no Cupid as clumsy as me.
Well... This kid is
going to be happy. Yeah.
Hmm, love letters, huh?
Brings back memories.
Ah, there was even a time
when I borrowed a book and there were
love letters stuck between every page.
- There's no way you have such memories.
- As expected of Gen Z.
Excellent at seeing through
things. You figured it out well.
- But now, the teacher is super popular.
- The right eardrum is catching... huh?
Don't you know the
teacher has quite a few fans?
The left eardrum
is catching too.
Hey, stop that.
Don't say things like that. Huh?
Isn't there a love letter stuck
in that book of yours, teacher?
No way that's true. Huh? A novel!
Ah! Found it!
A SURPRISING RECEIPT IN PAGE 5
Snack, weak whiskey...
4,800 yen.
More importantly,
teacher, is that book Dazai's?
Ah, yes. Want to read it?
When people think of Dazai, they often think
of No Longer Human or The Setting Sun...
They might have a strong
image of his long works,
but he wrote a lot of short stories too.
That's why there's also a drama
based on Dazai Osamu's work.
- A drama based on Dazai!?
- Yes.
FRIENDSHIP EXHANGE
ORIGINAL WORK BY OSAMU DAZAI
SHOWA 21 (1946)
The man visited just
a few days after I had
moved from Tokyo to my
hometown with my family.
Hey!
Hey, long time no see!
Oh, forgotten me? It's Hirata, your
classmate from elementary school.
How many years has it been?
Twenty years, huh?
"This guy has always been
arrogant, shameless, and selfish.
It's as if he thinks of
others as his servants.
The phrase "only good at bossing
others around" suits him well."
Hey!
"And I was the type who
couldn't speak up clearly."
Remember the fight we got into back then?
The scar you gave me with your scratch.
In that fight, I...
I acknowledged you just a little.
"How pompous, saying
he "acknowledged" me."
More importantly, you won't even
serve a drink to your friend of 20 years?
Serve him a drink.
Is that okay?
"I'll make sure he knows we
live in different worlds now."
Tastes like cheap shochu.
"Trying to make a guy like
this subtly realize something...
is impossible from the start."
You're proud that you
went to Tokyo, aren't you?
I never said anything like that.
If I had gone to Tokyo too...
I could've done as well as you.
But in the end, you
failed at a bunch of things...
And ran back here, didn't you?
Ah, something like that...
Well... if you're in trouble, just say so.
I wouldn't mind giving you advice.
"Like I'd fall for that.
If I show any weakness...
He'd just use it to blackmail
or boss me around."
Ahh, you're such a boring guy.
Ah, I'm drunk!
Hey... hey!
Call your wife in here.
- Huh?
- Just do it!
Call her in and let her serve me.
Did you call me?
Wife! Sit here.
This guy and I...
We used to fight a lot back in the day,
but I did judo and was strong,
so in the end, he'd always
cry and beg for forgiveness.
Right, isn't that so?
With his income, it must be hard
just to make ends meet, right?
If you ever get tired of him...
You can come to me, you know?
Wife, don't be so distant.
I'm this guy's best friend, after all.
"His arrogance is
seriously crossing the line."
Sorry, the baby is crying.
"Not being able to stop
this guy's rudeness...
probably lowered my standing as well."
Your wife isn't doing a good job.
If she were my wife,
I wouldn't let her act like that.
It's because your teaching is too soft.
"A terrible day...
But if I make him angrier and he gets out of
control, I wouldn't be able to handle it."
Boring...
Just looking at your annoying face
makes the drink taste bad.
I'm leaving!
"I was waiting for those words.."
- I'll take some of the alcohol with me.
- Go ahead.
"A bottle of sake is a small price to pay."
"I planned to say just
one thing at the end...
Don't act so high and mighty."
"Who do you think you are?"
Hirata.
Don't act so full of yourself.
Since childhood, you've
been looking down on people.
Don't make fun of others.
Who do you think you are?
What's wrong?
The feelings I've had
for him all this time...
Ended up being thrown back at me.
Huh?
"The hatred I felt...
was it directed at him?
Or was it at myself?
I couldn't tell anymore."
In other words, what I
thought was an inner voice
was actually heard out loud.
That's why he got so angry
- and stormed off, huh?
- No way that's true.
- Lack of reading comprehension, how sad.
- Teacher, without realizing it,
someone might also be thinking,
"Who do you think you are?"
Huh?
Don't act so full of yourself!
Sorry. About you... I...
Stop it! That's embarrassing!
Reacting to it, how sad.
In my mind, this completely
surpassed Ben-Hur.
Ben-Hur? What's that?
It's my favorite movie.
The running time is 3 hours and 32 minutes,
- with an intermission.
- It's long.
- Looking forward to next week too.
- Oh, but teacher—.
This drama ends in four episodes.
Huh...? Wait, this week is...
This week is the fourth episode.
Which means..!
IN WEEK 5, A SURPRISING DIFFERENT PROGRAM
"For those who want to watch
this drama again, head to TVer!"