- Fetal dismemberment surgery.
- Cutting?
Cutting?
Cutting the foal inside the mother horse.
Let's at least save the mother.
Please don’t cut!
- It’s crying "Stop!"
- What are you saying?
- Stop! Let go!
- Calm down, calm down!
- Don’t do that!
- It’s to save Fairy!
What about Snow Pearl?
We named it Snow Pearl!
We promised! We promised
to watch its growth forever!
Don’t kill it!
Are you okay?
Sorry, I can’t do this.
I just… something like that…
If that’s how you feel, then quit.
It’s better to stop aiming
to be a veterinarian.
Go home.
ENGLISH SUBTITLE BY CHRIZ KAYRIKO
Visit chrizkayriko.github.io
Here, if you’d like, take this.
Huh? This much?
- Oh, did you start working?
- Yeah.
Oh… but is it really
okay to take this much?
It’s fine, it’s fine.
Our kids have long since left home.
It’s just the two of us,
we can’t eat this much.
Oh? Isn’t that Satori-chan!
Sorry for suddenly coming home.
It’s okay, come home whenever you want.
I wasted money on a plane ticket.
I’m happy to see your face, Satori.
Did you start working?
Something happened, right?
In work, an old hairdresser
friend reached out
so I decided to help with kimono dressing.
I have work tomorrow too.
A customer is coming in for a pre-shoot
for their coming-of-age ceremony.
Yukiko’s furisode from her
coming-of-age ceremony.
(TN: Furisode is a type of
traditional Japanese kimono.)
- Mother’s?
- Yeah.
- You’ve seen it in photos, right?
Grandmother was grinning
from ear to ear in them.
Well, of course.
They said it would be
difficult to live until twenty.
You’ve heard she had a
congenital heart condition, right?
But mother passed away.
At 36.
Ah, it looks nice.
Wasn't it scary?
Wasn't it scary… giving birth to me?
Because childbirth can
bring unexpected things.
Shall we eat something delicious?
Sukiyaki? Yeah?
(TN: Sukiyaki is a Japanese hot pot dish.)
Sushi?
(TN: Sushi is a traditional Japanese dish that consists
of vinegared rice combined with various ingredients.)
Premium unagi! Right?
(TN: Unagi is the Japanese
word for freshwater eel.)
Yeah, yeah.
Was just an omelet really okay?
This is what I wanted to eat.
About earlier… childbirth…
When that child got married and said,
"I want to have a baby," I was against it.
It's not really something
I should tell you, but…
Pregnancy itself puts
strain on her heart,
and risking one's body just to give
birth. I thought it would be better not to.
Not just grandma.
Grandpa and everyone else around
were worried and tried to stop it.
But that child wouldn't listen.
Said, "I've had to hold back on so
many things because of my illness."
That child, who rarely ever
cries, let the tears flow then.
She said all the patience until now
was time spent becoming stronger.
So… it's okay, it's not scary.
If you're scared, you can't
make dreams come true.
Dreams?
She gave birth to you, risking life itself.
Grandma’s omelet
tasted like Mom’s cooking.
LILAC NO HANASAKU KEMONOMICHI
(THE PATH WHERE LILACS BLOOM)
Satori!
EPISODE 2/3: THE MEANING OF BEING BORN
Satori! This is bad! Wake up, wake up!
Watermelon delivery!
Yo.
Huh? Ehh?! Why!?
Why?
- Why are you running?
- Hey! Wait a sec!
Why, why, why? Hey!
Hey, coming all the way from
Hokkaido, that’s so kind of you.
- Take your time and relax, okay?
- Yes.
Satori, grandma has work, kimono dressing.
Ah, okay.
Please, go ahead.
- I didn't come here just for this.
- Yeah.
I just happened to be passing by.
Stopping by on the way home to Yokohama.
- Sorry for worrying you.
- I'm not worried at all!
- I did, though. But I didn’t!
- Satori!
Another friend is here. Look.
I chased after migrating birds and
before realizing it, I ended up here.
I caused everyone to
worry. I'm really pathetic.
Sorry, Kubo-kun, Ayaka…
"Kubo-kun," huh.
I’m just "Ayaka," but
it’s "Kubo-kun," huh.
Ah… Showing off, huh.
Wait, could it be his
name isn’t remembered?
It’s fine, fine, fine.
No, um, it's not that…
Ah, Kubo-kun, huh. His
name is Kubo Toritaro.
Why say such a lie?
Go ahead and eat
the watermelon, Toritaro.
I was gonna eat it without being told.
I remember it, it's Zansetsu-kun.
"Zan" as in unfortunate,
"setsu" as in falling snow.
The name comes from a bird. Huh?
In the story "Old Daizo and a wild goose,"
there’s a goose named Zansetsu.
Your father named it,
right? The ornithologist.
Your father is an ornithologist?
Yeah. He studies bird ecology and the
conservation of endemic species
and did ecological surveys
together since childhood.
I grew up naturally feeling close to birds.
Try reading "Old Daizo and a wild goose" sometime?
How should I put it? Maybe animals
are far more dignified than humans.
Even someone like me, who isn’t an
animal lover, ended up feeling that way.
Not an animal lover?
Huh? That’s unacceptable.
- I'm just not super passionate about them.
- Then why veterinary medicine?
How did you eat watermelon?
Huh? What do you mean?
At home, my mother carefully removed the
seeds and cut it into bite-sized pieces.
I wanted to just bite into it.
Father, on the other hand, made my two
older brothers take medical school exams
but for me, he said,
"Since you're a girl,
just go to the affiliated
women's university."
I wanted to rebel against such parents.
And as expected, I totally shocked them.
When I said, "I'm going to be a
veterinarian" they were speechless.
So, you want became
a vet to shock your parents?
I know it was shallow. Now, at least.
Unlike Satori, who truly loves
animals and wants to help them,
I didn't aim to be a vet with such feelings
so maybe it doesn’t suit me.
Me too… After all this,
maybe I can't go on.
It's better to give up on
becoming a vet. Go home.
I feel like it's impossible.
If Satori thinks it's impossible, then for
me, it’s a hundred times more impossible.
To be honest, I also…
…would like to confess something here,
- but nothing.
- Nothing? - Nothing.
Is it about studying veterinary
medicine, any confusion or anxiety?
- None.
- Aren’t the practicals tough?
- No.
- Doubts or worries?
- None.
- Nothing at all?
None. Really, nothing at all for now.
Bird-boy, who has not a single
cloud of doubt, is dazzling.
So, there’s not much to say, but…
Then just be quiet already.
For now, why not take
a bite of the watermelon?
Eat it however you like.
Eat watermelon and
live life the way you want.
Nice.
Then…
Satori too.
Eating watermelon and laughing together.
Thinking about it,
something as simple as that,
it was like a miracle for someone like
me, who had stopped going to school.
How is it?
Spicy!
Still not so easy, huh?
Write down the recipe after all.
I’ll have it ready for the
next time you come back.
Even if it’s made
according to the recipe,
there’s no guarantee it will be
close to your Mom’s taste.
I didn’t come back. I ran away.
Next time I come back,
I’ll bring souvenirs too.
I’ll properly return
home. Not just run away.
No need for souvenirs. I’ve
already received enough.
Knowing that such wonderful
friends were made over there,
that was the best souvenir.
It’s not like the anxiety
is completely gone.
If I keep running away
like this, I’ll regret it.
I’ll end up spending my
whole life unable to do anything.
A life of only running
away is not what I want.
- Thank you for your hard work.
- Thank you very much.
Oimo-chan was such a good girl today too.
- If anything comes up again.
- Thank you very much.
Welcome back.
A phone call would’ve sufficed,
but I thought it’d be better
to talk in person after all.
It's about the one Kishimoto-san rescued.
What’s wrong?
Is everything okay?
- Is there a problem?
- No, all fine now. It's doing great.
Not being able to find an owner
to take in the dog was a big issue.
But this time, Dr. Hisatsune
has decided to take it in.
Really?
I want to get your consent for that.
If Dr. Hisatsune is going to
take care of it, that’s a relief.
I would like to take it
in as a blood donor dog.
Blood donor dog?
A dog that donates blood.
- Blood donation…
- Yeah.
There are times when dogs
need blood transfusions too, right?
Kishimoto-san,
in Japan right now, there is
no blood bank for animals,
so there need to be dogs that can share
their blood for sick or injured dogs.
Is it cruel to take blood
from a dog to save another?
It’s true that there is pain when a
needle is inserted. There may also be fear.
There may be changes in physical
condition due to blood being drawn.
But by becoming a blood donor dog,
A dog that was abandoned by its owner can
find a new role and live in a new place.
Would you consider it that way?
Some dogs are treasured for
life without needing to do anything,
while others are thrown away like
garbage when they are no longer wanted.
And then there are those
that become blood donor dogs
and work to save the lives of other dogs.
Did you meet Shizuhara?
Meet once and have a proper talk.
It’s my fault.
Veterinarians treat animal
illnesses and save lives.
I only imagined that convenient,
idealized version of the job.
Having an ideal image of
any job is important, though.
It’s not really an ideal… My
thinking was just too naive.
It’s true that being a veterinarian is
not only about saving animals’ lives.
Sometimes, it also involves making
the difficult decision to end a life.
But those decisions vary
from person to person,
and they change with time and culture.
So, wouldn’t it be fine for you
to approach it in your own way?
- My own way?
- Yeah.
You heal animals’ illnesses and save lives.
Say, “I will only do this,”
and only do what you can.
That’s…
There is nothing in this world
that absolutely must be done.
Pronger, you’re in a great mood today.
Thank you.
The cafeteria menu is going to change.
Really?
I like the hamburger steak set meal.
Everyone’s favorite hamburger
steak set meal isn’t changing.
That’s a relief.
They use a mix of beef and
pork, right? That’s okay with you?
Huh?
Aren't the cows and pigs
made into hamburgers pitiful?
It's contradictory, right?
I like hamburgers too.
I won't eat them.
From now on, for the rest
of my life, hamburgers…
Just kidding, I will eat them.
Because they’re delicious.
I will eat them with
a feeling of gratitude.
I'm full of contradictions. Sorry.
Want to help a little?
Yes.
Then, please brush Pronger.
Okay.
My late father was also a veterinarian.
Ah, I heard that.
- From Kase-kun?
- Yes.
He was a clinical
veterinarian for racehorses,
he handles treatment
for illnesses and injuries,
vaccinations, and
disease prevention work.
On race days, he examined
the horses that were going to run,
and in case of an injury or accident,
he carried out rescue operations.
Apparently, he was quite skilled
and an excellent veterinarian.
And yet, he quit.
Why?
For example, do you know what
happens to a horse that can no longer run
or suffers a fatal injury?
Some get taken in by riding clubs or
retirement farms and can live in a new place
but some are euthanized.
My father, as a veterinarian,
he was in a position where
he had to make that decision.
Just like Dr. Nomi made the
decision during Fairy’s birth.
He loved animals,
and my father always
enthusiastically told me,
"I became a veterinarian
to save animals."
He talked about it with so much joy.
For my father, being forced to
make life-and-death decisions,
it must have been extremely painful.
It took a toll on his mental health,
and after resigning, he passed away.
He took his own life.
Just loving animals isn’t always
enough to overcome things.
There may be more
lives that cannot be saved
than those that can be
saved as a veterinarian.
The number of animals we humans
can save might be very limited.
Even so, I will become a veterinarian.
I will become a veterinarian
and embrace both the hopes
and despair that my father saw.
For my father’s sake as
well… I will cherish every life.
Right?
Thinking about life...
Whether it’s animals or humans…
Thinking about the preciousness
of life born into this world...
Thinking about its fleeting nature...
Thinking about human selfishness,
contradictions, convenience, and limitations.
Each time, resolving to
move forward, yet wavering...
Sometimes, wanting to run away again...
Being supported by those
around, and recovering...
Kuu, come! Stay.
Sometimes gaining
confidence, sometimes losing it...
Touch.
Through repeating such things,
days pass in the blink of an eye.
Ayaka, are you okay?
Let's take a break over
there. Can you walk?
I'm fine.
Continue.
To honor precious lives,
with a sincere resolve
that surpasses mere pity
we dedicate ourselves to
learning with all our hearts.
That's a whooper swan.
The shape of the black markings
on the beak is different.
When they become adults,
each one has a unique marking.
That’s how they can be
individually identified.
- Which one?
- That one.
Are you going out?
Satori and Zansetsu.
Huh? You guys get along well.
We're friends.
Why not just date already?
I don’t really get what “dating” means.
How is “being close friends”
different from “dating”?
Are you a kid?
Listen, the difference from a friend is
whether there's romantic feelings involved.
But you like friends too,
so you become close, right?
Do you feel nervous when you’re with them?
Oh, right, want to see this?
A long-tailed tit I photographed before.
Flying in the winter sky
while snow was falling.
You don’t feel nervous when
you’re with a friend, right?
Long-tailed tits have insulating
feathers, so they’re resistant to the cold.
Look, see this? It’s all fluffy.
You want to talk more, to know
more, never wanting to be apart.
You want to always
be by this person’s side.
Even in winter, they can
survive by sucking on tree sap.
Uh… Something feels really close.
Oh, sorry.
You don't want to give this
person’s side to anyone else!
Zansetsu-senpai. Do you have a moment?
- Go ahead.
- Oh, sorry!
Please, go ahead.
Um, about the upcoming test, there's
something I don’t understand…
Ah, this! This!
Too bad! No romantic feelings, huh?
But it's comfortable being together,
easy, and he gives a sense of security.
Love for animals and
romantic love are different.
Huh?
Kishimoto-san!
I have something important to
talk about with Kishimoto-san.
- Huh? With me?
- Yeah.
Grandma,
for the first time, I went to a café
with an adult man, just the two of us.
Thank you for waiting.
The most popular item in
the café is called crème brûlée.
The top part is burnt.
Kishimoto-san does
that kind of thing too, huh?
I couldn't say it was to send to grandma.
What is this talk about?
Ah, well...
With graduation approaching,
things are going to get busy.
The national exam
is also coming up.
So, there won’t be much time to
go to Nanakamado Animal Hospital.
That’s why, would you like
to work there in my place?
Me... At Nanakamado Animal Hospital?
Of course, there will be
a part-time wage,
and actually, Dr. Hisatsune
has already given permission.
Sorry. I don’t think I’m
capable of working yet.
- I think I’d just be a burden.
- No need to be so nervous.
When I first started working at that
hospital, I was still in my second year.
Dr. Hisatsune isn’t expecting
immediate results from you either.
There’s a desire of her to
teach you knowledge and skills.
So, just think of it as
an opportunity to learn.
- I volunteer!
- Huh?
- Ah... she’s also from Hokuno University.
- I enrolled this year.
I met Kase-san through
animal rescue volunteering.
But for a first-year, isn’t working
at an animal hospital still too hard?
You just said to work while learning.
That’s what I said just now...
If it’s for Kase-san, I’ll quit here!
Am I not good enough?
- Huh? It’s not about good or bad...
- Then I’ll...
- I'll do it!
- Huh?
I-If I’m okay...
- Really?
- Then, I will accept the offer.
I’m so glad.
Eh!?
Huh? Wait, one more time.
What did Kase-san say?
"I'm so glad."
That’s it?
"I'm so glad... I’ve always..."
I’ve always thought
Kishimoto-san was the right one.
It's about Nanakamado. At
Nanakamado Animal Hospital,
taking over Kase's position and
working there, it's best for me.
You're saying that,
but your face is smiling!
Not smiling!
- Grinning.
- Not grinning.
For that reason... I’ve
decided to start a part-time job.
I'm looking forward to working with you.
Until you're getting used
to it, I will drop by too.
Without overdoing it,
of course, studies come first.
Okay, here we go.
When the part-time job savings add up,
I will invite grandma to Hokkaido.
Come visit.
Let's eat crème brûlée together.
Chidori-san.
Oh, you shouldn't be awake.
You should be sleeping.
It's fine.
- Is this okay?
- Yeah.
- Should I make rice porridge?
- It's fine.
It's not fine, right?
Should you call Satori-chan?
It's fine.
Only saying "it's fine," geez.
ORAL MEDICINE
It's fine.
Hey, do you know Yamame and Sakuramasu?
- Fish?
- Yeah.
Exactly the same species
of the salmon family.
But when they grow up, they are
called Yamame and Sakuramasu
- with different names.
- Why is that?
It's whether they grew up
in the river or in the sea.
That difference changes their name?
Yeah. Then, why do they grow up
in different places, river and sea?
That is because of the strength of the
individual fish during the fry stage.
In other words, fry that are
big and strong as individuals
can get food where they were
born, so they stay in the river.
On the other hand, fry
that are small and weak
descend the river searching
for food and head to the sea.
The sea has an abundance of
food incomparable to the river.
Then, the fry that manage
to survive in the sea
can grow much bigger than
those that stayed in the river.
Yamame that grew in the river
at most reach around 30 cm,
while Sakuramasu that grew
in the sea can reach 50 cm.
A complete reversal.
Yeah, a complete reversal.
Even if small and weak…
Even if there are hardships
and one runs away,
with time, change is possible.
Those who have suffered are stronger than
those who could do everything from the start.
You can become stronger.
Even when you're with friends,
you don't feel nervous, right?
Shall we go?
It's gotten late. Let's
go straight home.
You want to talk more,
learn more, you don't want to be apart.
You want to be
next to this person forever.
You don't want to let anyone be next to this person!
What? Is something wrong?
Oh… the seatbelt…
Alright.
Ah, it's time.
Huh? What?
I'm going to Sapporo. A friend
from high school is visiting.
I'm going to be introduced to someone
special. Someone nice for Christmas.
- I hope there's someone who suits Mako.
- I'm getting excited.
Isn't Mr. Kishimoto going?
It's fine, this kid.
You should make up your mind already.
Yeah, how much longer
are you going to wait?
- Ehh?
- "Ehh? What are you talking about?"
Don't play dumb, it's Kase-san.
Kase-san... You can do
it, do it! Confess already!
Christmas is for this! Go for it!
Good luck. Yeah. Yeah.
See you then.
- I'm off.
- Take care. - Bye.
- Take care.
- Seems fun.
What about Zansetsu-kun? What
are you doing for Christmas?
Shizuhara-san, what are you doing?
I'm always busy with exam studies.
Maybe I'll just relax this Christmas.
Sounds good.
Kishimoto-san, can
you pass me that red one.
Alright.
Oh, found you!
We promised to go to
Furano to eat soup curry.
Ah, I forgot.
- So this is what you're doing.
- Sorry, sorry.
Kishimoto-san, are you
going too? He's treating us.
Hey, hey, hey.
Kishimoto-san?
Ah... I...
Ah, at Nanakamado, have
you gotten used to work?
Ah, yes. Thanks to
Dr. Hisatsune, I’m managing.
It’s a privately owned animal hospital, so
a lot of different pet owners come, right?
- Soup curry.
- I know!
Are you really that hungry?
You were the one who
said you wanted to go!
- What about Christmas?
- I am just going to relax?
No, no, "relaxing" means...
Let's drive to Furano.
It's fine if you don’t want to.
No, no, it’s just that I'm in
the mood for soup curry now.
That.
- Ah... sorry.
- No.
Is this... Zansetsu-kun's?
Mm... I chose it.
I brought it.
Because it’s a pair.
Pair?
There’s a partner.
How do birds find their partners?
With their feathers?
- Feathers?
- Yeah.
The patterns on birds’
feathers have meaning,
and they help identify if
they're the same species.
While flying, they instinctively look for
patterns on feathers that are the same as theirs.
They search instinctively.
Yeah. From there, they find
a partner and become a pair.
Ah, not just a pair, but it
also helps them form a flock.
Of course, there's also
"calling" to each other.
I see.
What about humans? I wonder
if humans are the same as birds.
Do they choose someone who suits them?
I wonder.
In romance, you might fall for
someone completely opposite,
but if you're going to be together for life,
someone with the same values works better.
It’s more likely to work.
Hmm? You talk a lot.
- Really?
- Ah, wait a minute.
Here.
Thank you.
I might not have much advice, but
I think you should express your feelings.
Huh?
You don't want to
regret not saying anything?
What are you talking about?
What am I really talking about?
How did you know?
Of course, I know.
But before I could express
my feelings, I got rejected.
You didn’t express them,
so you weren’t rejected.
From how it looks, Kase-san
and Shizuhara-san...
They might just be friends.
With such a good relationship?
We’re close too, but
we’re just friends, right?
That’s true.
Yeah. It’s true.
Ah, enough!
I want to be a bird.
I want feathers.
HOKUNO UNIVERSITY
AKEBONO DORMITORY
As expected, I couldn’t
tell my grandmother.
I couldn’t even get to confess.
MERRY CHRISTMAS
The fact that I ended up heartbroken.
"Merry christmas," I
just typed that and sent it.
I didn't notice that it hadn't
been read until the next morning.
UNKNOWN NUMBER
Yes.
Satori?
That was the first time
hearing it in a long time.
It was my father's voice.
Grandma...
NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW
There are people who have lived
believing in animals more than humans.
As long as you live, you live together.
As long as there's the will,
you can start over in any life.
I want to witness the
passing of the baton of life.
UPON CONSULTING WITH EXPERTS,
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED WHILE FILIMING.
ENGLISH SUBTITLES BY CHRIZ KAYRIKO
Visit chrizkayriko.github.io