If that day,
If grandma hadn’t come to see me,
in that house now,
I would probably still be living a
hidden life without anyone knowing.
Satori!
I’m sorry, for not knowing.
Well, I didn’t know this would happen.
Grandmother's chest was
warm, and it had a nostalgic smell.
At the age of 12, when I hit a
dead end and became a hikkikomori,
(TN: Hikkikomori will be defined later.)
my life started moving again.
Hmm, what is it?
What could it be? A dog?
It’s not a dog. If it were a dog, I’d know.
It’s kind of different from a dog.
Yeah... then what smell is it?
What smell is it?
When the wind blows...
Ah, look, now.
It smells faintly.
What is it?
Isn’t it this way? I think it’s behind us.
It’s not this way. There’s
no way it’s this way.
Hey, new students! Where are you
going? The boys' dorm is that way!
Hello!
What is this smell?
You figured it out. It’s
the smell of wild animals.
There’s a primeval
forest around here,
so occasionally the smell of
wild animals mixes with the wind.
Does that mean there
are wild animals nearby?
What do you think this place is?
There are foxes, raccoon dogs, and deer.
It’s natural to have wild animals here.
A wild animal trail, huh...
(TN: The term kemonomichi can also be referred as the path of wild animals but in the title of this drama, kemonomichi is used metaphorically to evoke a sense of a natural, untamed pathway where lilacs bloom.)
Well, even so, these birch
trees will bloom next month
and the lilacs will also be in full bloom.
It’s quite a beautiful wild animal trail.
Uh, everyone, are you the new
students of Hokuno University?
Nice to meet you. I’m Kase, the
dorm manager of the boys' dorm.
Kase-san.
I’m Chidori Ushiku, the
grandmother of this child.
Here.
Nice to meet you. Welcome
to Hokuno University.
If you’re new students,
shouldn’t you all greet each other?
- Ah, hello. How do you do?
- How do you do?
Saw it? That’s a fox, right? A fox.
Wow, after all, this
is a wild animal trail.
Huh? Look, look! Over there. Huh?
Three and a half years
have passed since that day,
and in the spring of '18, I
was in a new scenery.
The wild animal trail of becoming
a veterinarian that I chose,
was beginning to be walked slowly.
LILAC NO HANASUKU KEMONOMICHI
(THE PATH WHERE LILACS BLOOM)
ENGLISH SUBTITLES BY CHRIZ KAYRIKO
Visit chrizkayriko.github.io
EPISODE 1 (OF 3): BECOMING AN ANIMAL DOCTOR
New students, welcome to Hokuno
University Akebono Dormitory.
Orientation will be held from 19:00,
so please assemble in the cafeteria.
For things you don't understand…
Room 202?
I'm next door! Nice to meet
you! I am Shibano Mako.
Ah, sorry. Nice to meet you.
Coming in or not, which?
I am Shibano Mako. I'm next door.
- Which one will be used?
- Oh, she asked which one will be used.
About your bed...
- Upper, lower. Which?
- Which?
I said "which do you want"?
Ah, well, well, well...
Hey, look, first, go in?
HOKUNO UNIVERSITY
EQUESTRIAN CLUB
- Ah, Shizuhara-san?
- Yes.
- The head of the girls' dormitory?
Um, here... This is
nothing fancy, but please.
Ah… What is it here? If it's okay…
- Ah… sorry.
- No, no.
I am from Sendai.
Which part of Tokyo are you from?
Hey, what school are you from?
She hardly went to middle school.
Her high school is one that
accepts such children,
it's called a Challenge School.
A place for children who were
chronically absent or truant.
(TN: For more information about challenge schools, visit toritsuko.metro.tokyo.lg.jp/challenge/)
You were not attending school.
That child's mother... in other words,
my daughter, she died of illness, and
it was when that child was in fourth grade.
Two years later, a new mother came…
I thought for sure things were going well.
But then, she began spending
most of the day in room…
A so-called hikikomori?
(TN: Individuals who withdraw from social life and seek extreme isolation and confinement.)
Do those things have some
kind of trigger or something?
Sorry! I'm asking too bluntly.
I'm really not good at
this kind of thing, huh?
Really, I'm sorry!
I'm worried, worried about
whether she can get along with others.
She's good with words, but a
kind child, yes. She loves animals.
Then there's no need to worry, right?
What?
If animals are loved, that
means humans are loved too.
Humans are animals too, right?
Please believe in your grandchild.
Everything will be fine.
When the bus comes, go back.
I'll take you to New Chitose Airport.
There's no need to
worry, I can go home alone.
Grandma, aren't you worried?
Listen, considering
the transportation cost to the airport,
unnecessary spending isn’t an option.
We've talked about this, right?
Tuition and dorm fees aside.
The only money that can be
sent is from Grandma’s pension.
30,000 yen is the limit.
Alright? From now on,
think for yourself
and manage everything with
30,000 yen per month.
Ah, I almost forgot. Here.
What's this...?
It's savings set aside little by
little, use it aside from your allowance.
No, it's fine. I'll manage
with just the 30,000 yen.
Just take it! It's a charm from Grandma.
Grandma, I'm sorry.
Why are you apologizing?
At times like this, you
should say, "Thank you."
Satori...
When you want to say something
important, speak loudly and clearly, okay?
Use diaphragmatic breathing like this.
Okay?
Do your best.
Once again, I'm Satori Kishimoto!
I have no preference for
the top or bottom bunk!
Nice to meet you!
So, either the top or
bottom bunk is fine with me!
Grandma, how are you?
The days of studying in the veterinary
program at Hokuno University have begun.
So, for horses and pigs,
their placenta structure
consists of an epithelial
villous placenta.
How should I put it... Every day is
fresh, filled with surprise and emotion.
From an outsider’s perspective,
it might not seem that way,
but inside my head, I’m constantly
shouting things like “Wow!” or “Whoa!”
Or even “This is insane!”...
My emotions are running wild.
During practical training, through
smells, textures, sounds, and sights,
I use all five senses to grasp
the essence of an animal’s life.
What it means to be alive.
And also... Do you remember the male
student I met at the white birch-lined road?
The one who was happy to see a fox…
Ah, no, that’s not it. No, no.
That sparrow! I was taking
a picture of that sparrow.
You're making a face like "A
sparrow isn’t anything special."
Actually, the number of
sparrows in Japan is decreasing.
According to a nationwide survey,
compared to 20 years ago,
the number of sparrows has
decreased by more than 30%.
That was suppose to be the part where
you will be surprised at like, "Really!"
What are you doing?
What are you talking about?
- Sparrows.
- Ah, sparrows.
A sparrow talk seemed
like it would go on forever,
but Kase-san saved the day.
Kase-san runs an animal protection club
and takes care of abandoned dogs and cats.
Then, what happens if treatment is needed?
- Take them to Hisatsune-sensei.
- Hisatsune-sensei?
Yes. The director of an animal
hospital further down the national road.
Alright, I'm going to
touch a little. You're so cute!
Ah, good boy, good boy. Such a good boy.
A strong and kind doctor
who always helps for free.
There’s a big nanakamado tree in the yard,
so it’s called “Nanakamado Animal Hospital.”
(TN: Nanakamado is commonly known as
the Japanese Hackberry or Celtis sinensis.)
Oh, I see.
Do you know the flower
language of the nanakamado tree?
“I will protect you.”
So cool!
Grandma, I wonder
if one day I can become strong
enough to protect someone, too.
I hope I can.
Grandma,
I am doing well.
I'll send you a sunset from Hokkaido.
Yukiko, look.
Alright. Alright.
Alright!
Good night.
This is a problem.
Is there no way to do something about this?
Like I’ve said many times,
room changes are not
possible at this time of year.
If a room change isn’t
possible, I will leave the dorm.
- Kajita-san.
- That’s enough. Excuse me.
Why not try talking it out
properly, just the two of you?
Impossible! Gross!
It’s impossible for me!
- Nice...
- Hm? What?
Shizuhara-san, you're loved by
both animals and people.
Me? Really?
I'm jealous… it's from the
perspective of someone like me.
Someone like me is like a black cat.
Why a black cat?
Called ominous, called creepy…
Just crossing in front of
people, but already disliked…
But black cats…
They don’t understand at all
why they’re being disliked.
They don't understand?
They can only run away.
Kishimoto-san’s grandmother,
she was so, so worried about you.
I said, “Please believe in her,” and all…
Kishimoto-san isn’t a black cat.
Because you can speak words.
There must be something you
can do besides running away.
HOKUNO UNIVERSITY
AKEBONO DORMITORY
So! Since Shizuhara-san
said that, as for me…
- What are you trying to say?
- What do you…
So, you think I’m creepy…
- Yeah, you're creepy.
- So, what part?
Right there.
That. That’s creepy.
- What is…
- There, right there!
What are you talking about?
What are you saying? It’s right there!
This. This.
This!
At night, you're secretly taking
it out and mumbling something.
Thought I wouldn’t notice?
Normally, anyone would.
I kept wondering and wondering, what
are you doing, what’s inside.
- Did you look?
- Having something like that is creepy enough
but that thing itself is creepy.
I’ve had enough. Get rid of it!
- Um!
- What?
- Let me explain!
- Explain what?
- This… what’s inside this…
- Don’t open it. I saw it so I know it.
It's bones.
I said I know.
Though I don’t know whose bones.
- It's Pearl's…
- Pearl? Foreigner?
- A dog.
- A dog?
These are a dog’s bones.
- Why dog bones?
- Let me explain!
You know I’m listening!
It is okay? To speak?
Hurry up and speak.
When I was born…
Starting from birth?
When I was born,
Pearl wasn't there yet.
Let's start from when Pearl was there.
Pearl came when I was three years old
and was named by my late
mother. Pearl was originally a rescue dog.
Your mother passed away?
When I was fourth grade, due to illness.
After that, I lived with my father
and Pearl, just the three of us.
Then, in sixth grade,
my father remarried a former subordinate
from work, and I got a new mother.
At first, I tried to get along.
But then my father was
transferred away alone
and things started going
wrong in many ways.
What happened to Pearl?
Pearl was my only emotional support.
And yet, Pearl died.
Pearl passed away on the day of
my exam results announcement.
As if Peal was reassured
after confirming my acceptance,
Pearl peacefully took the last breath.
I see.
But still, you're bringing
it? In such an old box?
Not to be rude, but
isn't that going too far?
I guess kids who stop going
to school are just different.
This old box…
It once held a
strawberry birthday cake.
For my 10th birthday, before
passing, my mother bought it.
Besides this, barely
anything of my mother's remains…
When my new mother came,
she started throwing away my
mother's things one after another.
I begged many times not to throw them
away, but they were still discarded.
The only thing left that
my mother cherished was Pearl…
But even Pearl, the new mother disliked it
and she started saying to get rid of Pearl.
I firmly refused, but then,
next, she claimed dog allergies,
she said her eyes itched, her nose
wouldn't stop running, so get rid of Pearl
or better yet, just
abandon Pearl somewhere.
I said that was impossible, but then,
I was told to keep Pearl locked
in the room and never let out.
It was scary.
That was the reason of me stopping school.
I feared that while at school,
Pearl would be abandoned.
Honestly… I wanted to go to school.
I wanted to go, just like everyone else.
But… Pearl… was always on my mind.
You're such an idiot!
Good morning.
Good morning!
Grandma, I learned that even
without diaphragmatic breathing,
if spoken with effort,
people will understand.
Here in Hokkaido, when
the lilac flowers bloom,
the temperature can suddenly
drop sharply. It's called "Lilac Chill."
Ah, lilac is called
"lilas" in French.
- Huh? Which way was it?
- Which way was it?
Today, we went out to Sapporo.
I might not be able to choose!
Grandma… sorry.
I bought a dress at a thrift store.
It's 1,980 yen. Sorry!
Because…
A welcome party for new students
called Shirakaba Festival is being held.
(TN: The Shirakaba Festival is about celebrating the beauty of
nature and traditional arts. Shirakaba means "white birch." )
- Huh? Is this the right way?
- Yeah, let's hurry.
Is there something wrong?
It sounded like, an animal crying.
- A fox?
- Let's go quickly. - Yeah.
Do you think there'll be a lot of people?
WELCOME PARTY FOR NEW STUDENTS
2022 SHIRAKABA FESTIVAL
If you’d like, crouch
down and try touching it.
Swallows generally migrate to Japan
from March to April And build nests, right?
So when I saw it,
I thought there must be chicks in the nest.
What are you talking about?
So, my guess is they’re
having a second breeding cycle.
- Hello!
- So cute! You both look great!
- Really?
- At least give a compliment there.
Where’s Kishimoto-san?
Are you lost?
You're wearing a collar.
Where's your injury?
- Injury?
- What’s wrong?
A dog. A lost dog.
Senpai!
Kishimoto-san?
- Are you alright?
- Yes.
Hisatsune-sensei.
The nanakamado doctor…
Hisatsune here. You spotted it.
Please take care of it.
Someone must have abandoned it.
They're getting a pet easily, then
realizing how hard it is to care for
and giving up when they can't handle it.
Ah, making an "unforgivable" face?
But that's the reality of some people.
From the animals' perspective,
human ego is crystal clear.
Be careful.
While studying veterinary medicine, there
are times when one starts to dislike humans.
Now, go back.
Today is the Shirakaba Festival, right?
That one is fine now, so
return with peace of mind.
Come on, off you go!
Ah, here they come!
Was everything okay?
- Good.
- That’s a relief.
But… that dress...
A sign of having saved a
life without regard for oneself.
- No, no, it’s not like that.
- No exaggeration.
If left alone, that one
might have lost its life.
Even Professor Hisatsune was
impressed, saying it was well spotted.
Good work.
Ah, thank you.
Well done.
Well done!
Stop it.
So, why isn’t Kajita-san coming?
It’s the perfect chance
to witness a horse’s birth.
Kajita-san… Ayaka is bad with blood.
Rather, why is Kubo-kun here?
Being bad with blood is a fatal flaw, huh.
That’s why there’s been a struggle
over her not being suited for being a vet.
It's still too early to tell
if she's a good fit or not.
That’s what I said too.
These past few months, I’ve been
thinking… this really isn’t for me.
Again with this?
But the motivation is so impure.
My parents are doctors, my older brother is
a doctor, so naturally, I just follow suit.
And when med school
seemed impossible,
I switched to becoming
an animal doctor instead.
It's way too casual.
It's still too early to tell
if you're a good fit or not.
No, it’s obvious. Compared to Satori,
there’s none of that ‘I love animals with
all my heart and soul!’ kind of feeling.
Just now… “Satori,” huh…
It’s no longer that distant “Kishimoto-san”
or “Kajita-san” level anymore.
Eh? What kind of distance, then?
This kind of distance.
I'm too happy about this.
OGAWA FARM
This is our ranch.
My uncle is the owner, but it’s
also my mother’s family home.
I grew up here.
Uncle.
Oh, Kazuma.
Long time no see. Thank you for taking
care of me during last year’s training.
When that’s done,
change the bedding straw.
Got it.
Is labor progressing?
- Ah… I have no idea.
- How is it?
The udder is quite swollen,
so it might be progressing a lot.
Fairy, stay calm. It’s okay.
We’re here with you.
Is the name Fairy?
Yeah. Fairy Snow, Snow Fairy.
The foal that’s about to
be born, you all can name it.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- I’ll grab a quick meal while I can.
- Got it. - Okay.
So, what should we name it? Huh?
I want to call it by name as
soon as it’s born. Let’s decide now.
How about Snow White? Not quite?
- Snow Flower.
- Snow… Bell.
- Oh! Snow Bird!
- No birds!
- Snow Pearl.
- Pearl?
Pearl, huh… I like it.
Snow Pearl… Snow’s pearl…
Nice. Snow Pearl it is!
Even after graduating from university,
let’s not forget about Snow Pearl
and keep watching over its growth.
Promise.
Promise!
Crying?
Hang in there… Hang in there, Fairy.
Hang in there.
It’s okay. It’s okay.
Kazuma, call Dr. Nomi.
- Tell him to come right away.
- Got it!
Is something wrong?
Do you know the normal process of delivery?
First, the water breaks…
Then the amniotic sac… Two front
legs facing downward come out.
Front legs, nose, face,
head, shoulders, in that order.
That’s right, in a normal case.
But right now, those
front legs aren’t visible.
What does that mean?
It looks like it’s stuck inside.
Then just pull it out? Like with a cow?
If you pull too hard, you’ll
injure the outer cervix.
Then what should we do?
- Dr. Nomi!
- Sorry for being late.
- No, sorry for calling you so suddenly.
- When did the water break?
It’s been over an hour already.
Kase, get the dystocia kit.
Yes! Kubo-kun, help out a bit!
Yes!
How does it look?
It's tough…
What about a C-section?
Even if surgery is done
now, the foal won't survive.
Take-san, it's unfortunate,
but let's give up this time.
- No way!
- There's no choice.
At this rate, Fairy is in danger too.
- Let's at least save the mother.
- Please.
How will you save her without a C-section?
Ah… I see. So that's how it is.
- Kubo-kun, bring that over here.
- Yes.
Thanks.
What happened?
- Fetotomy.
- Cutting it?
Cutting?
The foal will be cut
inside the mare’s womb.
What?
- It's for Fairy.
- Hey, you two go outside.
No, I'm staying here.
I'll stay by
Fairy’s side and watch the procedure.
Then, you two go outside.
I was thinking of recording
a video… but this isn’t the time for that.
USHIKU CHIDORI:
SATORI, HOW ARE YOU?
Satori, how are you doing?
Thanks for always sending so many pictures.
This time, I'll send one from grandma.
You've been working
hard, even during summer break,
doing practical
training and assignments.
You’ve been
trying so hard, it makes me admire you.
Do you remember when grandma
asked, ‘Satori, do you have a dream?’"
- I don’t know.
- You don’t know?
I’ve never even thought about it.
Then let’s think about it.
About the future, a dream.
A dream… is it okay to have one?
Of course it is!
What about a job related
to animals like Pearl?
Since you love animals,
maybe that kind of path suits you? Right?
That kind of path?
A veterinarian. A doctor for animals.
No way. Someone like me…
It's impossible, impossible, impossible.
Even while saying that, something began
to bloom inside Satori's heart.
- Grandma could see it.
- Grandma…
I…
Yeah…
I’ll try it!
Yes! Yes!
Satori, please walk with confidence.
I’m always cheering for you, good luck!
Grandma...
Can I take Pearl's bones with me?
Because of Pearl, I
thought maybe I’d become a veterinarian...
I want to stay close
to animals who can’t speak like Pearl,
and listen to their voices properly.
That's how I feel... So...
Stop...
Stop!
Please don’t amputate!
- It’s crying "Stop!"
- What are you saying?
- Stop! Let go of me!
- Calm down, calm down!
- Don’t do that!
- It’s to save Fairy!
What about Snow
Pearl? Snow Pearl! We named it Snow Pearl!
We promised! We
promised to watch its growth forever!
We promised!
Please stop! Stop!
No! Stop! Don’t kill it!
Stop! Please!
NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW
It’s better to stop aiming
to be a veterinarian.
If you’re scared, you won’t
be able to make your dreams come true.
There is nothing that
you absolutely have to do.
Hey!
I think you should express your feelings.
I want to become a bird.
AFTER CONSULTING WITH EXPERTS, NO ANIMALS
WERE HARMED WHILE FILIMING.
ENGLISH SUBTITLES BY CHRIZ KAYRIKO
Visit chrizkayriko.github.io